停下.
SNAKE: Stop.
狼：如果你向我解释一下，我就不说了，
WOLF: I'll stop if you just explain it to me,
-因为我不-请你放下它好吗？
-because I don't... -Would you please just drop it?
狼：好吧，好吧，好吧，好吧，好吧，好吧.
WOLF: All right, all right, fine, fine, fine, fine.
就当它掉了.它掉了.
Consider it dropped. It's dropped.
-它在地上-好的
-It's on the ground. -Good.
但是，我是说，拜托，每个人都喜欢生日.
But, I mean, come on, everybody loves birthdays.
-（呻吟）-你有装饰品.
-(groans) -You got decorations.
你有气球.你有派对和蛋糕.
You got balloons. You got parties and cake.
听着 我不需要礼物，
Look, I don't need presents,
我不想要装饰品，我也不喜欢蛋糕.
I don't want decorations, and I'm-I'm not a cake guy.
说真的，你不喜欢蛋糕吗？
Seriously, though, you don't like cake?
说出一种比蛋糕更好的食物.
Name one food better than cake.
豚鼠.
Guinea pig.
哦，又是豚鼠.
Oh, again with the guinea pig.
（笑）：我打赌如果我蒙住你的眼睛，
(chuckling): I bet if I blindfolded you,
你不可能分辨出区别
you wouldn't be able to tell the difference
在臭鼬和豚鼠之间.
between a skunk and a guinea pig.
错误的蛇的味蕾无可挑剔.
Wrong. Snakes have impeccable taste buds.
-我能尝到空气的味道-空气
-I can taste air. -Air?
对空气
Yes. Air.
（咕噜咕噜）
(slurping)
嗯.美好
Mm. Nice.
我不知道.他们有点...
I don't know. They're a little, uh...
我觉得有点可爱.
a little cute for my taste.
这就是它们如此美味的原因.
That's what makes them so delicious.
你不仅仅是在吃东西.
You're not just eating food.
你吃的是纯粹的善良.
You're eating pure goodness.
这与猪无关.
It's not about the pig.
它在更深层次上象征着什么.
It's about what it symbolizes on a deeper level.
所以，你可以...你能尝到空气的味道吗？
So, you can... you can taste air?
-（呻吟）-你还有什么？
-(groans) -What else you got?
-算了吧-等等.
-Forget about it. -W-W-Wait.
-你也能听到颜色吗-（呻吟）
-Can you also hear color? -(groans)
-（笑）你能看到声音吗-好吧，好吧.可以
-(chuckles) Can you see sound? -All right, all right. Okay.
因为我们真的应该利用这些技能.
'Cause we should really be capitalizing on these skills.
好吧，好吧.把一切都说出来.
Okay, all right, fine. Get it all out.
-现在把它全部拿出来-好的，好的.
-Get it all out now. -Okay, okay.
-（干呕）-（警铃响）
-(retches) -(alarm bell dings)
看看这个.下午四点.
Look at that. 4:00 p.m.
现在我知道我们友谊的确切时间了.
Now I know the exact moment our friendship died.
（狼笑了）
(Wolf laughs)
-让我们跳起来-是的.
-Let's bounce. -Yep.
尝起来像是，你又要给我账单了.
Tastes like, um, you're gonna stick me with the bill-- again.
-（人们喘着粗气）今天是我的生日.
-(people gasping) -Well, it is my birthday.
你现在玩生日卡了？
So now you play the birthday card?
-这很有趣-（咯咯笑）
-That's interesting. -(chuckling)
当你有机会的时候，能给我们一张支票吗？
Can we get a check, please, when you get a chance?
你好检查检查.
Hello? Checkity-check-check.
-你知道吗-（尖叫声）
-You know what? -(screams)
我们就把钱留在这里，好吗？
We're just gonna leave the money right here, okay?
你知道这地方的一个优点吗？
You know the one good thing about this place?
-什么-我们从来不用等桌子.
-What? -We never have to wait for a table.
这不是每个地方吗？
Well, isn't that every place?
嘿，伙计.最近怎么样？我好久没见到你了...
Hey, man. How you been? I haven't seen you in...
-蛇攻击！（笑）-（尖叫）
-Snake attack! (chuckles) -(screaming)
哦薄荷糖.
Oh. Mints.
抱歉，各位.我要把他换成无咖啡因的.
Sorry, folks. I'm switching him to decaf.
（咯咯笑）
(chuckles)
好吧
All right.
-两个：让我们这样做-（入口铃声）
-BOTH: Let's do this. -(entry bell jingles)
-（人们喘息、尖叫）-（轮胎尖叫）
-(people gasping, screaming) -(tires squealing)
-（撞车）-（汽车警报声）
-(crashing) -(car alarm whooping)
-（轮胎发出尖叫声）-（撞车声）
-(tires squeal) -(crashing)
豚鼠？
Guinea pig, huh?
这是啮齿动物中的劳斯莱斯.
It's the Rolls-Royce of rodents.
是的，但它还是一只啮齿动物.
Yeah, but it's still a rodent.
你知道我的意思吗？
You know what I mean?
-别介意我们，只是抢劫这个地方-（喘息）
-Don't mind us, just robbing this place. -(gasping)
（尖叫、疯狂的喋喋不休）
(screaming, frantic chatter)
-（咔哒声）-（尖叫声）
-(clattering) -(screaming)
（警报响起）
(alarm ringing)
（发动机转速、轮胎吱吱声）
(engine revs, tires squeal)
哇！是 啊
Whoo! Yeah!
-变坏-或者回家.
-Go bad... -Or go home.
（两人都笑了）
(both laugh)
嘿，你.过来.
Hey, you. Get over here.
再近一点.
Little bit closer.
哦，我知道是什么.
Oh, I know what it is.
你害怕是因为我是...大灰狼.
You're afraid because I'm the... the Big Bad Wolf.
我并不惊讶.
Well, I'm not surprised.
我是每个故事中的反派.
I am the villain in every story.
是吗，斯内克先生？
Isn't that right, Mr. Snake?
（咯咯笑）：是的.
(chuckling): Yep.
向斯内克先生问好.
Say hello to Mr. Snake.
蛇形的，安全的破碎机.
Serpentine, safe-cracking machine.
想象一下胡迪尼没有手臂.
Imagine Houdini but with no arms.
那种会告诉你杯子有一半空的人，
Kind of guy who'd tell you the glass is half empty,
然后从你那里偷来.
then steal it from you.
他也是我最好的朋友.
He's also my best bud.
今天是他的生日！
(singsongy): And today's his birthday!
-不相关-他是个甜心.
-Not relevant. -He's a sweetheart.
-你是个甜心-（警报声哀鸣）
-You're a sweetheart. -(sirens wailing)
看看谁来了.
Well, look who's here.
-花了他们足够长的时间-（发动机转速）
-Took 'em long enough. -(engine revs)
看这个.
Watch this.
三
Three.
二一
Two. One.
这里是狼蛛女士，
And over here is Ms. Tarantula,
我们的内部黑客，我们的袖珍搜索引擎，
our in-house hacker, our pocket search engine,
我们的旅行科技向导.
our traveling tech wizard.
我们叫她网.
We call her Webs.
（警报声）
(sirens whooping)
（喇叭声）
(horns honking)
非常光滑，蜘蛛网.
Very slick, Webs.
我还接手了警方的调遣，
I also took over the police dispatch,
模糊了他们的卫星成像系统，
blurred their satellite imaging system,
他们的直升机停飞了.
grounded their chopper.
（辛格）：还有一件事.
(singsongy): And one more thing.
你没有.
You didn't.
我收到了一份特快专递...
I got a special delivery for...
啊！哦！别吃我！
Ah! Ooh! Don't eat me!
请别吃我！
Please! Don't eat me!
生日快乐，暴躁先生.
Happy birthday, Mr. Grumpy Pants.
我想我恨你.
I think I hate you.
（发动机转速）
(engine revving)
（施工设备发出哔哔声）
(construction equipment beeping)
（警报声哀鸣）
(sirens wailing)
（军官们呻吟着）
(officers groaning)
（咯咯笑）：伙计们，是我.
(chuckling): Guys, it's me.
我是建筑工人.
I was the construction worker.
这是Shark先生，
WOLF: And this is Mr. Shark,
伪装大师，
master of disguise,
一千张脸的顶级捕食者.
apex predator of a thousand faces.
他最大的把戏：偷蒙娜丽莎
His greatest trick: stealing the Mona Lisa
-伪装成蒙娜丽莎-（警报声哀鸣）
-disguised as the Mona Lisa. -(sirens wailing)
明白了.
Dig that.
小心点，大金枪鱼.
Watch it, big tuna.
我想在这里工作.
I'm trying to work here.
保持冷静，宝贝.
Keep it cool, baby.
生日应该很冷.
Birthdays should be chill.
（警报声哀鸣）
(sirens wailing)
沃尔夫：还有把全体船员集中起来...
WOLF: And rounding out the crew...
（砰砰）
(thumping)
惊喜
Surprise!
（食人鱼大笑）
(Piranha laughing)
狼：...是食人鱼先生.
WOLF: ...is Mr. Piranha.
他是个脾气暴躁的大炮，
He's a loose cannon with a short fuse,
愿意与任何人或任何事断绝关系.
willing to scrap with anyone or anything.
-他很勇敢-（咯咯笑）
-He's brave. -(cackling)
-（喊叫）-他无所畏惧.
-(yelling) -He's fearless.
我在跟谁开玩笑？他疯了.
Uh, who am I kidding? He's crazy.
（笑）Santo cielo，这是一个很大的波波.
(laughs) Santo cielo, that's a lot of po-po.
食人鱼，我们忘了什么吗？
Uh, Piranha, did we forget something?
-什么-礼物.
-What? -The present.
-你知道-哦，嗯...
-You know. -Oh, um...
我当然没有忘记.
Of-of course I didn't forget.
-（嘟嘟）-你知道你撒谎的时候会放屁，对吗？
-(toots) -You know you fart when you lie, right?
什么不，我紧张的时候放屁.
What? No, I fart when I'm nervous.
是 啊害怕撒谎.
Yeah. Nervous about lying.
-（肚子咕噜）-（呻吟）对不起.
-(stomach burbling) -(groans) I'm sorry.
-（大声放屁）-其他：食人鱼！
-(loud fart) -OTHERS: Piranha!
鲨鱼：不要吸入.
SHARK: Don't breathe it in.
-我吸进去了-（军官们呻吟着，喘息着）
-I breathed it in! -(officers groaning, gasping)
狼：是的，他们有点古怪，
WOLF: Yeah, they're a bit eccentric,
但当你生在我们身上时，你并不一定会赢
but when you're born us, you don't exactly win
许多人气竞赛.
many popularity contests.
-（呜咽）鲨鱼-其他：鲨鱼！
-(whimpers) Shark! -OTHERS: Shark!
我希望人们不要把我们当成怪物吗？
Do I wish people didn't see us as monsters?
八条腿，是有氧运动的八倍.
Eight legs, eight times the cardio.
怪物
Monster!
-狼：当然，我知道-怎么了，爸爸？
-WOLF: Sure, I do. -What's up, papa?
狼：但这些是我们发的牌，
WOLF: But these are the cards we've been dealt,
所以我们还是玩吧.
so we might as well play 'em.
头奖
Jackpot!
对
Yes!
（轮胎发出刺耳的声音）
(tires screech)
嗯...
Um...
-胸部是什么-你疯了吗？
-What the thorax? -Are you crazy?
什么我只是想再追一次车.
What? I just wanted a longer car chase.
这是最好的部分.
It's the best part.
（模糊的无线电聊天声）
(indistinct radio chatter)
首领是...
Chief! It's...
他们
Them.
（咕哝）
(grunts)
韦伯斯，点击.
Webs, hit it.
（“停、落、滚”不能停也不会停）
("Stop, Drop, Roll" by Can't Stop Won't Stop playing)
抓住他们！
Get them!
（大笑，呼喊）
(laughing, whooping)
（喧闹）
(clamoring)
-（轮胎吱吱声）-（汽笛声）
-(tires squealing) -(sirens wailing)
*痴迷于嘻哈语音*
* Hooked on hip-hop phonics *
*是的，对我有用*
* Yeah, it works for me *
*所以跳上车，是的，这列火车是免费的*
* So jump aboard, yeah, this train is free *
*售票员，让我吹口哨*
* The conductor, let me toot my whistle *
*时髦叔叔菲斯的教练*
* The instructor of the funky uncle fizzle *
*当湖面还没有结冰的时候，我们在湖面上跳舞*
* We be dancin' on a lake when it ain't froze over *
*我们在水上行走，而你在下沉你的漫游车*
* We be walkin' on water while you're sinkin' your rover *
*如果你再靠近一点，你就会吃到牙齿*
* If you step any closer, you'll be eatin' some teeth *
*所以请退后一步*
* So please step back... *
（笑）
(laughing)
我要把你们关起来这么久，
I'm gonna put you guys away for so long,
你的跳蚤会有跳蚤.
your fleas will have fleas.
（咕哝）
(grunts)
（喘息）
(all gasp)
首领你想吃蛋糕吗？
Chief. You want some cake?
-你好像有点难受-（笑声）
-You seem a little hangry. -(laughter)
在我...
Get that thing out of my face before I...
-对不起，警长-什么
-Excuse me, Chief. -What?
-（尖叫）——*停下*
-(screams) -* Stop *
*下降*
* Drop *
*滚，滚*
* Roll, roll *
*停*
* Stop... *
（警报响起）
(sirens blaring)
（笑）你是我的.
(chuckles) You're mine.
*滚*
* Roll... *
（发动机转速）
(engine revs)
赫尔马诺.
Hermano.
（轮胎吱吱作响）
(tires squealing)
（尖叫）
(screaming)
*我要拿我的，我的，我的，真的*
* I'm gonna get mine, mine, stake mine, really *
*Chi Town猫像费城一样吃奶酪*
* Chi-Town cat gettin' cheese like Philly *
*在烧烤店点牛排，我觉得很冷*
* Order steak at the grilly, I flow chilly... *
（都在尖叫）
(all screaming)
（鸟儿啁啾）
(birds chirping)
（都在尖叫）
(all screaming)
*你是个鸡块头，在我的聊天中蘸一蘸*
* And you's a chicken nugget head, dip it in my chitchat *
-*停下…*-（扣咔嗒声）
-* Stop... * -(buckles click)
是的，我们可能很坏，
Yeah, we may be bad,
但我们很擅长.
but we're so good at it.
（笑声）
(laughter)
-（警报声尖叫）-（咕噜声）
-(sirens wailing) -(grunts)
*住手*
* Stop *
*放下*
* Drop... *
哦，不，不，不，不，不，不，不！
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
继续跑，狼！
Keep running, Wolf!
总有一天你会走运的！
One of these days, your luck is gonna run out!
（歌曲结尾）
(song ends)
（钟声）
(bell dings)
好了，食人鱼，你起来了.
All right, Piranha, you're up.
*哦*
* Oh... *
*快乐小鸟*
* Happy bir... *
-（吹）-（喘息）
-(blows) -(gasps)
-真的吗-狼：蛇，来吧.
-Seriously? -WOLF: Snake, come on.
-至少干杯-（蛇呻吟）
-At least make a toast. -(Snake groans)
-干杯！来吧-来吧
-Toast! Come on! -Come on.
-好的，好的.好吧干杯-哇！
-SNAKE: Okay, okay. All right. A toast. -Whoo!
好的
Fine.
在我的时代，我树敌很多，我是说，很多--
I've made a lot of enemies in my time-- I mean, a lot--
但是在世界上所有的人当中，
but out of all the people in the world,
我最不恨你们了.
I hate you guys the least.
-啊-这真是太美了.
-Aw. -That was actually kind of beautiful.
你是个诗人，伙计.
You're a poet, man.
斯内克先生和他对生日的奇怪厌恶.
To Mr. Snake and his strange dislike of birthdays.
-狼蛛：耶-（其他人尖叫、大笑）
-TARANTULA: Yay! -(others whooping, laughing)
每个人都说“抢劫”
Everyone say, "Robbery."
全部：抢劫.
ALL: Robbery.
（笑）：哦.
(chuckles): Oh.
看看那些酒窝.
Look at those dimples.
-生日快乐，伙计-可以
-Happy birthday, buddy. -Okay.
-现在，加油，伙计们-对
-Now, dig in, fellas. -Yes!
-（大笑，疯狂地咀嚼）-食人鱼！
-(laughs, munches wildly) -Piranha!
-狼：别这样-（食人鱼咕噜咕噜）
-WOLF: Don't do that. -(Piranha slurping)
狼蛛：太恶心了.
TARANTULA: That was so gross.
鲨鱼：那是我的午餐！
SHARK: That was my lunch!
-食人鱼：你打盹，你输了-（狼蛛笑）
-PIRANHA: You snooze, you lose. -(Tarantula laughing)
-狼：你喜欢那样-（食人鱼咯咯笑）
-WOLF: You like that. -(Piranha chuckles)
美好的
Nice.
-哦，哇-（喘息）
-Ooh, wow. -(gasps)
我忘了我们有推瓶.
I forgot we had those Push Pops.
伙计，我的肚子现在像海怪一样隆隆作响.
Man, my tummy is rumbling like a kraken right now.
是 啊想要吗？
Yeah. Want it?
你知道他不会给你的.
You know he's not gonna give it to you.
不，我内心深处相信
No, I believe that deep down
蛇是一个善良而慷慨的灵魂.
Snake is a kind and generous soul.
为什么？
Why?
在这里拿去吧.
Here. Take it.
（笑）：哦，是的！
(laughing): Oh, yeah!
请给我开门.
Pop me, please.
-啊-哈
-Ah... -Ha!
（笑）笨蛋.
(chuckles) Sucker.
来吧，伙计.现在你要让我变得咄咄逼人.
Come on, man. Now you gonna make me get all aggressive.
-（喧闹）-动物.
-(clamoring) -Animals.
吐出来！吐出来！
Spit it out! Spit it out!
从不
Never!
让我们看看他们今天在说什么.
Let's see what they're saying about us today.
怎么了？这里是Tiffany Fluffit，第六频道动作新闻.
What up? It's Tiffany Fluffit, Channel 6 Action News.
坏人又袭击了...
The Bad Guys have struck again...
伙计们，伙计们，住手.我们在电视上.
Guys, guys, stop it. We're on TV.
-哦，哦！-...再次证明他们
-Ooh, ooh! -...proving once more that they
是我们这个时代最邪恶的罪犯.
are the most diabolical criminals of our time.
哦，“恶魔”这是新的.
Ooh, "diabolical." That's new.
知道这听起来像什么吗？古龙水.
Know what it sounds like? A cologne.
（戏剧性地）：恶魔般的.
(dramatically): Diabolical.
蒂芙尼：为了应对这场令人发指的犯罪狂潮
TIFFANY: To address this heinous crime spree
是新当选的州长黛安·福辛顿.
is the newly elected governor, Diane Foxington.
-州长-黛安：好的.是 啊
-Governor? -DIANE: Okay. Yeah.
-我听到了.我听到了-（记者叫嚣）
-I hear you. I hear you. -(reporters clamoring)
听着，听着.我们都知道坏人有多卑鄙.
Listen, listen. We all know how dastardly the Bad Guys are.
-狼：当然了-但最重要的是...
-WOLF: You bet we are. -But more than anything...
（笑）我为他们感到难过.
(chuckles) I feel sorry for them.
什么
What?
这些所谓的坏人
These so-called Bad Guys
都是二流的.
are really just second-rate has-beens.
在他们业余的滑稽动作背后
Behind their amateurish antics
坦率地说，还有一些非原创的胡闹--
and, frankly, unoriginal capers--
我是说，真的，另一家银行--
I mean, really, another bank?--
只不过是一口愤怒的深井...
is nothing but a deep well of anger...
我没生气！你生气了！
I ain't angry! You're angry!
-...否认-不是真的.
-...denial... -Not true.
...自我厌恶.
...and self-loathing.
我唯一讨厌的人就是你.
The only one I self-loathe is you.
这些漏洞没有多少现金
And those are holes that no amount of cash
或者说无价的艺术永远无法填满.
or priceless art can ever fill.
食品网络上有什么？
What's on the Food Network?
黛安：那么，我们能不能忘了...
DIANE: So, can we just forget about...
她是谁来评判我们？
Who-who is she to judge us?
-黛安：...专注于更积极的事情-（咆哮）
-DIANE: ...and focus on more positive things? -(growls)
还有什么比这更积极的呢
And what could be more positive
比一年一度的好撒马利亚奖，
than the Annual Good Samaritan Awards,
明晚我将在那里展示金海豚
where tomorrow night I will present the Golden Dolphin
献给今年最优秀的公民？
to this year's goodest citizen?
我不敢相信我投了她的票.
I can't believe I voted for her.
你投了她的票？
You voted for her?
狼蛛：什么？她擅长气候变化.
TARANTULA: What? She's good on climate change.
等待发生什么事？
Wait. What's going on?
你的眼睛闪闪发光.
You've got that twinkle in your eye.
伙计们，谁要换工作？
Guys, who's up for another job?
一个大的.
A big one.
（喘息）
(all gasp)
金色海豚.
SNAKE: The Golden Dolphin.
-真的吗-哦
-Seriously? -Oh.
我以为我疯了.
I thought I was the crazy one.
那项工作使每一个尝试过的罪犯都崩溃了.
That job has broken every criminal who's tried it.
布加勒斯特强盗，幸运的吉姆.
The Bucharest Bandits, Lucky Jim.
鲨鱼：深红色的爪子.
SHARK: The Crimson Paw.
事实上，那只深红色的爪子从未被捕.
Actually, the Crimson Paw was never arrested.
是的，但他再也没偷过东西了.
Yeah, but he never stole anything again.
斯内克，还有更好的办法吗
Snake, what better way
擦掉州长模糊的脸上的假笑
to wipe that smirk off the governor's fuzzy face
而不是偷金海豚
than stealing the Golden Dolphin
就在她胡子底下？
from right under her whiskers?
这是盗窃的圣杯.
This is the Holy Grail of thievery.
如果我们成功，我们将巩固我们的遗产
If we pull this off, we'll cement our legacy
作为史上最伟大的罪犯.
as the greatest criminals of all time.
伙计.
Whoa, whoa, buddy.
我以为我们不该把事情说成是私事.
I thought we weren't supposed to make things personal.
此外，我们有一件好事要做.
Besides, we've got a good thing going here.
朋友们，自由，看看这些战利品.
Friends, freedom, and just look at this loot.
好吧，你说得对.算了吧.
All right, you're right. Forget it.
-海豚队的任务结束了-好的
-The Dolphin job is off. -Good.
我猜猪终究会得到他的奖杯.
I guess the pig will get his trophy after all.
是的，我想他会...
Yeah, I guess he would...
“猪”是什么意思？
What do you mean, "pig"?
哦，是的，我没提吗？
Oh, yes, did I not mention that?
真奇怪.我想我提到了，呃...
That's weird. I thought I mentioned that it was, uh...
善良的撒玛利亚人是...
The Good Samaritan is...
一只豚鼠？
A guinea pig?
（咕噜咕噜）
(slurping)
你说呢，斯纳基？
What do you say, Snakey?
比蛋糕好.
Better than cake.
-（笑声）-狼蛛：对.
-(laughter) -TARANTULA: Right.
（呻吟）好的.好的
(groans) Okay. Fine.
但他最好是美味的.
But he better be delicious.
（笑）我们都在一起吗？
(laughs) Are we all in this together?
计划是这样的.
So here's the plan.
和每年一样，仪式也将举行
Like every year, the ceremony will be held
在美术馆，
at the Museum of Fine Arts,
金海豚将被安置在哪里
where the Golden Dolphin will be positioned
就在后台的幕布后面.
just beyond the backstage curtain.
听起来很简单.
Sounds easy.
听起来很容易，赫尔曼诺，但要达到目的，
Sounds easy, hermano, but to get there,
我们需要绕过三个安全级别.
we'll need to bypass three levels of security.
所以，第一步：我们需要融入其中.
So, step one: We'll need to blend in.
（“为你嚎叫”由黑键演奏）
("Howlin' for You" by The Black Keys playing)
*宝贝，我在为你嚎叫*
* Baby, I'm howlin' for you *
*达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达达*
* Da-da da-da da, da-da da-da da... *
Marmalade教授，
WOLF: Professor Marmalade,
今年的金海豚奖得主，
this year's recipient of the Golden Dolphin,
地球上最令人讨厌的好生物.
the most annoying good creature on the planet.
教授，在过去的一年里，你停止了战争，
Professor, in the past year, you've stopped wars,
给饥饿的人喂食，拯救了无数的熊猫.
fed the hungry and saved countless pandas.
有些人描述了你的善良
Some have described your goodness
仅次于特蕾莎修女.
as second only to Mother Teresa.
哦，蒂芙尼，这不是比赛.
Oh, Tiffany, it's not a competition.
如果是的话，那就更像是平局了.
And if it were, it would really be more of a tie.
但我们都同意，有一朵善良之花
But we can all agree that there is a flower of goodness
在我们所有人的内心，等待着绽放.
inside all of us, just waiting to blossom.
狼：一进门，就有两扇装甲门.
WOLF: Once inside, there are two armored doors.
第一个只能由
The first can only be opened by
随身携带的特殊钥匙卡
a special key card that is carried
我们亲爱的朋友，警察局长.
by our dear friend, the chief of police.
第二台装有视网膜扫描仪
The second is outfitted with a retinal scanner
由一支精英特种部队守卫
and guarded by an elite special ops unit
经过训练，可以先罢工，然后再提问.
trained to strike first and ask questions later.
-（苍蝇嗡嗡声）-（嗖嗖声）
-(fly buzzes) -(whooshing)
福辛顿州长是唯一一个
Governor Foxington is the only one
他有打开第二扇门的许可.
who has clearance to open the second door.
所以，第二步：她和我需要
So, step two: She and I will need to get
近距离的和私人的.
up close and personal.
祝你晚上愉快，大使先生.
Enjoy your evening, Mr. Ambassador.
谢谢你，女士.
Thank you, ma'am.
很有意思.
Interesting piece.
无用的、毫无意义的、自命不凡的.
Trashy, pointless and pretentious.
他们说艺术揭示了
Hmm. They say that art reveals
与其说是艺术家，不如说是观众.
more about the viewer than the artist.
-（笑）-先生...
-(chuckles) -Mister...
普德尔顿.奥利弗·普德尔顿.
Poodleton. Oliver Poodleton.
黛安：嗯...可以
DIANE: Uh... okay.
是时候有人站起来了
It's about time someone stood up
给那些邪恶的坏蛋.
to those diabolical Bad Guys.
不过，我得说，还没有人成功.
Though, I've got to say, no one's succeeded yet.
嗯.我觉得没那么难.
Eh. I don't think it'll be that hard.
我感觉会比你想象的更难.
I have a feeling it'll be harder than you think.
我得说他们就差一个史诗般的工作了
I'd say they're one epic job away
巩固他们的遗产.
from cementing their legacy.
-（黛安笑了）-（狼笑了）
-(Diane laughing) -(Wolf chuckles)
普德尔顿先生，你真有趣.
Mr. Poodleton, you're-you're funny.
我是？
I am?
他们正在巩固的唯一遗产是终身监禁.
The only legacy they're cementing is life in prison.
你看到他们上一份工作了吗？
Did you see their last job?
啊.安全出口，
Ugh. Unsecured exits,
粗鲁的伪装，强迫性的表演.
crude disguises, compulsive showboating.
我是说，那是一团糟.
I mean, it was a mess.
船员衰落的所有经典迹象.
All the classic signs of a crew in decline.
下一步，他们会把它变成私人的.
Next, they're gonna make it personal.
这时你就知道他们是土司了.
That's when you know they're toast.
（笑）：嗯，那是你的意见.
(chuckles): Uh, well, that's your opinion.
是的，我是州长.
It is, and I'm the governor.
至于雕塑，我认为它是关于透视的.
As for the sculpture, I think it's about perspective.
如果你仔细观察，
If you look closely enough,
即使是垃圾也可以被回收成美丽的东西.
even trash can be recycled into something beautiful.
狼：怎么样？
WOLF: How about that?
我猜有些事情并不总是表面上的样子.
I guess some things aren't always as they appear.
这提醒了我.
That reminds me.
我可以吗？我不能错过拍照机会
May I? I can't miss a photo op
州长和一堆垃圾.
with the governor and a pile of garbage.
哦，普德尔顿先生，你对自己太苛刻了.
Oh, Mr. Poodleton, you're too hard on yourself.
-嘿-（相机咔哒声）
-Hey... -(camera clicks)
（安静的闲聊、笑声）
(quiet chatter, laughter)
好的，朋友们.
WOLF: Okay, friends.
表演时间到了.
It's showtime.
一旦我们进入，就进入第三步：
Once we're in, it's on to step three:
我们分道扬镳，各就各位.
We split up and we take our positions.
警官们，如果坏人破坏了这场比赛，
Officers, if the Bad Guys crash this event,
我肯定会失业，
I am definitely going to lose my job,
我会毫不犹豫地把你带走.
and I will not hesitate to take you down with me.
-现在，搬出去-警官：是的，女士！
-Now, move out. -OFFICERS: Yes, ma'am!
小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，
Hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut,
小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋...
hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut...
麦克风开了.所有人都在通话，收到了吗？
Mic's on. Everyone on comms, do you copy?
-收到-收到-复制
-Copy. -Copy. -Copy.
（高音）：收到.
(high-pitched voice): Copy.
（笑）
(laughs)
给这位漂亮女士喝一杯？
A drink for the pretty lady?
不用了，谢谢.我现在的生活太复杂了.
No, thank you. My life is too complicated right now.
呃，呃...
Uh, uh...
（吹口哨）
(whistling a tune)
孩子们，这是海豚的季节.
Boys, it's Dolphin season.
（低声咕哝）
(muffled grunting)
（裤子拉链）
(pants zip)
收到.我要走了.
Copy that. I'm on the move.
第二单元，后台区域还安全吗？
Unit two, is the backstage area still secure?
警官（通过无线电）：第二单元.一切正常.
OFFICER (over radio): Unit two. All clear.
这是所有培训的回报.
This is where all the training pays off.
-（咕哝，呻吟）-哦，原谅我.
-(grunts, groans) -Oh, pardon me.
-非常抱歉-没问题，先生.
-Terribly sorry. -Not a problem, sir.
孩子们，睁大眼睛.
Keep your eyes open, boys.
他们可能在任何地方，只是等着羞辱我们.
They could be anywhere, just waiting to humiliate us.
（笑）
(laughs)
狼已经就位了.
Wolf is in position.
（通过广播）：食人鱼，你们都穿着企鹅服，穿着靴子吗？
(over radio): Piranha, you all penguin-suited and booted?
肯定的我是一个干净，卑鄙，偷海豚的机器.
Affirmative. I'm a clean, mean, Dolphin-stealing machine.
怎么了，伙计们？
What's going on, guys?
（隐约的喋喋不休）
(indistinct chatter)
（咕哝）
(grunts)
（女人咕哝着）
(woman grunting)
（两声尖叫）
(both yelp)
（女人喘着气）
(woman gasping)
（叹息）
(sighs)
-来，我来帮你-哦.
-Here, let me help you. -Ooh.
你没事吧，夫人？
Are you okay, ma'am?
（喘息）：哦，天哪，是的.
(panting): Oh, my gracious, yes.
我可能会头晕，但多亏了你，我还活着.
I may be dizzy, but I'm alive, thanks to you.
-狼：你是什么-哦
-WOLF: What are you... -Oh.
嗯.
Mm.
（狼呜咽）
(Wolf whimpers)
谢谢你，亲爱的.
Thank you, dear.
你真是个好孩子.
You're such a good boy.
（轻声笑）
(chuckles softly)
（女人咕哝着）
(woman grunting)
（呜咽）
(whimpers)
好吗，兄弟？
All good, brother?
是的，所有...很好.是的，是的.
Yeah, all... a-all good. Yeah, yeah.
嗯...（噼啪声）
Um... (splutters)
韦伯斯，继续第四步怎么样？
Webs, what do you say about moving on to step four?
收到.Shark，你起来了.
Copy that. Shark, you're up.
-做你的事-（喘息）我可以即兴创作吗？
-Do your thing. -(gasps) Do I get to improvise?
是的，很好.即兴创作
Yes, fine. Improvise.
但请小心点.
But please be subtle.
嗯.
Mm-hmm.
（高音）：我要生孩子了！
(high-pitched voice): I'm having a baby!
有医生吗？
Is there a doctor?
或者几个保安
Or perhaps several security guards
可以离开他们的岗位帮助我吗？
that could leave their post and help me?
-（两人都喘着粗气）-（客人喃喃地说）
-(both gasp) -(guests murmuring)
（电梯铃响）
(elevator bell dings)
（锁发出哔哔声）
(lock beeping)
“鱼惊喜”？
"Fish surprise"?
惊喜（大叫）
Surprise! (yells)
（警卫咕哝着）
(guards grunting)
嘿，韦伯斯，你能把这个...
Hey, Webs, can you enhance this...
狼蛛：完成了.你前面八步，沃尔夫.
TARANTULA: Done. Eight steps ahead of you, Wolfie.
（笑）
(laughs)
播音员：女士们，先生们，
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
你的好心人奖主持人...
your emcee for the Good Samaritan Awards...
（喘着粗气）
(breathing heavily)
沃尔夫（通过无线电）：好了，鲨鱼，我们进去了.
WOLF (over radio): All right, Shark, we're in.
（正常声音）：哎呀，我忘了，我没有怀孕.
(normal voice): Oops, I forgot, I'm not pregnant.
播音员：...委员会主席，
ANNOUNCER: ...president of the committee,
戴安·福辛顿州长.
Governor Diane Foxington.
非常感谢.非常感谢.非常感谢.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you so much.
非常感谢.
Thank you.
去年，我们面临着最大的考验
Last year, we faced our biggest test
当一颗陨石撞上我们亲爱的城市.
when a meteorite crashed into our dear city.
那颗陨石不仅在我们的城市里留下了一个洞.
That meteorite didn't just make a hole in our city.
它在我们心中留下了一个洞.
It made a hole in our hearts.
-人群：哦-（鲨鱼抽泣）
-CROWD: Aw. -(Shark sniffles)
但即使在悲剧中，Marmalade教授，
But even in tragedy, Professor Marmalade,
他做得很好.
he did what he does so well.
他让我们用不同的眼光看待事物.
He made us look at things differently.
多亏了你，果酱，
And thanks to you, Marmalade,
爱情陨石坑将永远成为一个象征
the Love Crater Meteorite will forever serve as a symbol
即使在最糟糕的地方也有好的一面.
of how there is good even in the worst places.
（掌声）
(applause)
哇！
Whoo!
（黛安模糊地继续说）
(Diane continues indistinctly)
（食人鱼大笑，咕哝）
(Piranha laughs, grunts)
（咕哝）
(all grunt)
（呻吟）快点.
(groans) Hurry up.
（咕哝）
(grunts)
...成功扭转了气候变化
...and successfully reversed climate change
为了我们所有人的幸福.
for the well-being of all of us.
事情进展得出人意料地顺利.
This is going surprisingly smoothly.
（喘息）
(gasps)
（狼叫声）
(Wolf yelps)
那是什么蜕皮？
What the molt is that?
狼：狼食人鱼蛇鲨狼蛛
WOLF: The Wolf Piranha Snake Shark Tarantula
-保护系统-狼蛛：WPSST？
-Protection System. -TARANTULA: The WPSST?
-这是不应该发生的-什么
-This was not supposed to happen. -What?
伙计们，冷静点.我会的.
Guys, calm down. I'm on it.
正在启动WPSST覆盖协议.（咯咯笑）
Initiating WPSST override protocol. (chuckles)
明白了，皇后！
Get it, queen!
（电脑嗡嗡响）
(computer buzzes)
-狼：有用吗-给我五分钟.
-WOLF: Did it work? -Just give me five minutes.
现在，请和我一起欢迎来到舞台上...
And now, please join me in welcoming to the stage...
我们没有五分钟了.
We don't have five minutes.
...Marmalade教授.
...Professor Marmalade.
哦.
Aw.
我们爱你，果酱教授！
We love you, Professor Marmalade!
猪在动.
The pig is on the move.
我再说一遍，猪在动.
I repeat, the pig is on the move.
织网，织网，窗帘随时都会升起.
Webs, Webs, the curtain's going up any minute.
它不让我进去.
It's not letting me in.
检查你的系统偏好.
Check your system preferences.
你可能需要下载一个驱动程序.
You probably need to download a driver.
尝试重新启动.
Try rebooting.
天哪，你修好了.
Oh, my gosh, you fixed it.
-蛇和狼：真的吗-不
-SNAKE and WOLF: Really? -No!
-警长：嘿，拉里.
-(door rattling) -CHIEF: Hey, Larry.
来吧，开门.
Come on, open up.
关于锁门我们说了什么？
What did we say about locking doors?
哦，不，不，不，不，不，鲨鱼，我这里有情况.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. Shark, I got a situation here.
鲨鱼：收到.我在路上.
SHARK: Copy that. I'm on my way.
-（肚子咕噜）-（咕噜声）
-(stomach burbling) -(grunts)
快点，伙计们.
Hurry up, guys.
是时候让这个婴儿进入野兽模式了.
Time to turn this baby on beast mode.
吃了它，WPSST！
Eat it, WPSST!
拜托，现在不行.（呜咽）
Please, not now. (whimpers)
-狼-等等，等等，等等.不，不，食人鱼！
-Wolf. -Wait, wait, wait. No, no, Piranha!
-这个奖是给-（食人鱼放屁的声音很大）
-This award is for... -(Piranha farts loudly)
（清了清嗓子）就像我说的...
(clears throat) As I was saying...
不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不！
(gasps) No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
（嗅嗅）
(sniffing)
-食人鱼！你在开玩笑吗-食人鱼：对不起！
-Piranha! Are you kidding me? -PIRANHA: Sorry!
这就是为什么我的慈善晚会
And that's why my Gala for Goodness
将为那些不幸的人筹集所需的所有资金.
will raise all the money needed for those less fortunate.
-警长：来吧-（砰砰地敲门）
-CHIEF: Come on! -(pounding at door)
（深深地吸气）
(inhales deeply)
我开始生气了，拉里.
I'm starting to get mad here, Larry.
-狼：网！网-（低声咕哝）
-WOLF: Webs! Webs! -(muffled grunting)
现在是我们一直在等待的时刻.
And now the moment we've all been waiting for.
-（呜咽）哇！
-(whimpering) -Whoa!
（呻吟）
(groans)
鲨鱼（高音）：对不起.
SHARK (high-pitched voice): Excuse me.
这是女厕所吗？
Is this the ladies' room?
你得右转
Oh, uh, y-you need to take a right
在大厅的尽头，女士.
at the end of the hall, ma'am.
（喘息）
(gasping)
对哇哇！
Yes. Whoop-bam!
哦，来吧！
Oh, come on!
现在我很荣幸授予Marmalade教授
And now it is my honor to award Professor Marmalade
和金海豚一起！
with the Golden Dolphin!
-（喘息）不-不.
-(gasps) No. -No.
（正常声音）：是的！
(normal voice): Yes!
（高音）：我是说，是的！
(high-pitched voice): I mean, yes!
什么
What?
（尖叫声）
(screams)
大家，大家，请不要惊慌.
Everyone, everyone, uh, please don't panic.
保持冷静.
Just stay calm.
我相信这是有原因的.
I'm-I'm sure there's an explanation for this.
（喘息，低语）
(gasping, murmuring)
我再说一遍，请不要惊慌.
I repeat, uh, please do not panic.
大家干得好.
Nice work, everybody.
现在，让我们像狼一样，把狼群带出去.
Now, let's make like a wolf and get the pack out of here.
啊，文字游戏.
Ah, wordplay.
我不明白.
I don't get it.
果酱：黛安，黛安，如果我可以...
MARMALADE: Diane, Diane, if I may...
-（麦克风反馈尖叫声）-你必须理解，
-(microphone feedback squeals) -You have to understand,
我没有为获奖而把希望带回城市.
I didn't bring hope back to the city for an award.
我做这些好事是因为它们给我的感觉.
I did these good things because of how they made me feel.
我有种刺痛的感觉.
That tingly feeling I get.
让我脊梁骨颤抖.
That shiver up my spine.
我的小尾巴在摇摆.
The wag in my tiny tail.
因为，你看，
Because, you see,
感觉很好.
being good just feels so good.
当你很好的时候，你会被爱.
And when you're good, you're loved.
-（喘息，呜咽）-狼？
-(gasps, whimpers) -Wolf?
-狼-你在做什么？
-Wolf? -What are you doing?
蛇、鲨鱼和食人鱼：走！
SNAKE, SHARK and PIRANHA: Go!
-是坏人-（客人尖叫）
-It's the Bad Guys! -(guests screaming)
逮捕他们！
Arrest them!
警察：小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，
OFFICERS: Hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut,
小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，
hut, hut, hut, hut, hut,
小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋.
hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut.
（警察咆哮）
(officers growl)
他们偷走了金海豚！
They stole the Golden Dolphin!
拜托，你不能证明这一点.
Come on, you can't prove that.
（高音）：我的宝贝！
(high-pitched voice): My baby!
-跪下，坏蛋-（指关节裂开）
-On your knees, Bad Guys. -(knuckles crack)
举起手来.
With your hands up.
从不我们要走了.
Never! We're out of here.
再见，笨蛋.
So long, suckers.
这有点奇怪.
Well, this just got a little weird.
（警报声）
(siren whooping)
蒂芙尼：坏人破产了.
TIFFANY: The Bad Guys go bust.
邪恶的五人组终于被抓获了.
The nefarious fivesome has finally been captured.
我Tiffany Fluffit是第一个到场的.
And I, Tiffany Fluffit, am first on the scene.
哇！我刚刚意识到我
Wow. You know, I-I just realized that I have devoted
我的整个成年生活都是为了把你关进监狱.
my entire adult life to putting you in jail.
你是我的目标.
You are my purpose.
没有你，我是谁？
Without you, who am I?
我只是开玩笑.
Ah, I'm just kidding.
这是我一生中最美好的时刻！
This is the best moment of my life!
-（啪）-（狼呜咽）
-(smack) -(Wolf whimpers)
这是坏人的末日.
It's the end of the Bad Guys.
不
No!
把手拿开！（尖叫声）
Get your hands off of me! (screams)
哦，你现在求我咬你一口.
Ooh, you're begging for a biting right now.
狼
Wolf!
蒂芬妮：果酱教授！州长女士！
TIFFANY: Professor Marmalade! Madam Governor!
哦，果酱教授！州长女士！
Ooh, Professor Marmalade! Madam Governor!
-州长女士-一次一个.一次一个.
-Madam Governor! -One at a time. One at a time.
-嘿.嘿-打扰一下
-Hey. Hey! -Excuse me.
-（人们屏住呼吸）-抱歉打断一下.
-(people gasp) -Sorry to interrupt.
我只是想祝贺这里的州长.
I just wanted to congratulate the governor here.
我得说，你真的让我们陷入困境.
I got to say, you really got us pegged.
我们只是一口充满愤怒和自我厌恶的深井.
We're just a deep well of anger and self-loathing.
-否认-当然那也是.
-Denial. -Sure. That, too.
-自恋-是 啊是 啊
-Narcissism. -Yeah. Yeah.
情感空虚.
Emotional emptiness.
-所以我们在同一页上-隐马尔可夫模型.
-So we're on the same page. -Hmm.
他在干什么？
What is he doing?
遗憾的是，我们从来没有机会
Sadly, we were never given a chance
比二流罪犯还要厉害.
to be anything more than second-rate criminals.
要是有人能帮忙就好了
If only there was someone who could help
我们内心善良的花朵盛开.
the flower of goodness inside us blossom.
爱与宽恕的象征，
Some icon of love and forgiveness,
比如，呃，我不知道，特蕾莎修女.
like, uh, I don't know, Mother Teresa.
最好的办法就是把我们关进监狱
Best thing is to just throw us in jail
在我们绝望的余生里.
for the rest of our hopeless lives.
是的，这就是计划.
Yeah, that's the plan.
-等等，等等，等等，不，不
-Wait, wait, wait, no, no. -(grunting)
-进去-噢
-Get in there. -Ow!
果酱：等等.
MARMALADE: Wait.
求你了...请再说一遍？
Uh, beg... beg pardon?
沃尔夫先生可能是一头凶猛的野兽.
Mr. Wolf may be a savage beast.
基本上是步行垃圾.
Basically walking garbage.
抱歉，我想说的是.
Sorry, I'm making a point.
做你该做的，伙计.
Do what you need to do, pal.
但我们怎么能说他们没有希望呢
But how can we say they're hopeless
如果他们从来没有机会？
if they've never been given a chance?
如果…怎么办...如果我们做个小实验呢，黛安？
What if... what if we tried a little experiment, Diane?
如你所知，我为上帝举办的晚会，
As you know, my Gala for Goodness,
“年度最佳慈善活动”即将揭晓.
the "hashtag charity event of the year," is coming up.
如果我能在晚会上向大家证明
If I can prove to everyone at that gala
坏人变了，
that the Bad Guys have changed,
你会让他们自由，给他们一个干净的开始吗？
will you set them free and give them a clean start?
（人群喘息、低语）
(crowd gasping, murmuring)
-什么？果酱教授-狼：噢！
-What? Professor Marmalade! -WOLF: Ow!
不不你没看到他在干什么吗？
No, no, no, no, no. Don't you see what he's doing?
他在耍你.
He's playing you.
但这是我的主意.
But it was my idea.
这是他的主意.
It was his idea.
但只是因为你让他得到了它.
But only because you made him have it.
州长夫人，你不能让他们走.
Madam Governor, you can't just let them go.
教授，我不会为了城市的安全
Professor, I'm not about to put the safety of the city
正在排队做实验.
on the line for an experiment.
对不起，州长女士.
Excuse me, Madam Governor.
我似乎记得一位智者曾经说过，
I seem to remember that a wise person once said,
“即使是垃圾也可以被回收成美丽的东西.”
"Even trash can be recycled into something beautiful."
（轻声笑）
(chuckles softly)
可以我很高兴.
Okay. I'm game.
只是因为是你，教授.
But only because it's you, Professor.
不
No!
我们会抓住海豚直到晚会.
We'll hold on to the Dolphin until the gala.
只是为了消除任何不必要的诱惑.
Just to remove any unnecessary temptation.
当然好主意.
Of course. Good thinking.
这就是为什么你是州长.
That's why you're governor.
现在大家都很开心...
Now that everyone's happy...
不开心.
Not happy.
...一、 Rupert Marmalade第四，
...I, Rupert Marmalade the Fourth,
会把坏人变成...
will turn the Bad Guys into...
-好人-（摄像机咔嗒声）
-the Good Guys! -(cameras clicking)
（人们喘着粗气）
(people gasping)
我想这些是你的.
I think these belong to you.
嘿
Hey.
黛安：不是每个人都有第二次机会.
DIANE: Not everyone gets a second chance.
充分利用它，普德尔顿先生.
Make the most of it, Mr. Poodleton.
（发动机起动）
(engine starts)
（警报声哀鸣）
(sirens wailing)
-蛇：狼？
-(chuckles) -SNAKE: Wolf?
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
-狼：什么-其他人：是的.
-WOLF: What? -OTHERS: Yeah.
哦，那个.（咯咯笑）
Oh, that. (chuckles)
对不起.我觉得这很明显.
I-I-I'm sorry. I thought it was, uh, obvious.
我们会顺利的.
We're gonna go good.
你完全失去了我.
Uh, you totally lost me.
我告诉他不要在厕所外喝酒.
I told him to stop drinking out of the toilet.
嘿，你的头被击中了吗？
Hey, did you get hit on the head?
什么不，我的头没有被击中.
What? No, I didn't get hit on the head.
我表弟的头被锚击中了，
My cousin got hit on the head with an anchor,
在那之后，他只游了一圈.
and after that, he only swam in a circle.
狼：不，不，哥们，哥们，你们没跟着我.
WOLF: No, no, g-guys, guys, you're not following me.
我们要假装一切顺利.
We're gonna pretend to go good.
就几天吃果酱.
Just a few days with Marmalade.
然后我们以好人的身份参加晚会
And then we roll into the gala as Good Guys
推出苏格兰免费的...
and roll out scot-free with...
所有人：金色海豚.
ALL: The Golden Dolphin.
你明白了.
You got it.
我们什么时候才能完成一项工作？
Since when do we not finish a job?
坏人变成好人
The Bad Guys become the Good Guys
所以我们可以留下来对付坏人.
so we can stay the Bad Guys.
-你知道我在说什么吗-（笑声）
-You know what I'm saying? -(laughter)
坏人表现得好吗？
Bad Guys acting good?
这是最坏的家伙.
It's the ultimate Bad Guy thing.
太棒了.
It's fantastic.
沃尔夫，你是个天才.
Wolf, you're a genius.
（笑声继续）
(laughter continues)
这将是有史以来最轻松的骗局，
It's gonna be, like, the most relaxing con ever,
就像度假一样.
like a vacation.
哦，哦.一场辩论.
Oh, oh. A con-cation.
（笑声）
(laughter)
鲨鱼：哦！我父母是在一次会议上认识的.
SHARK: Ooh! My parents met on a con-cation.
（海鸥呱呱叫）
(seagulls squawking)
（橘子酱嗡嗡作响）
(Marmalade humming)
（门铃响了）
(doorbell rings)
哦，太好了.
Oh, goody.
狼（咯咯笑）：哇.
WOLF (chuckling): Wow.
又大又漂亮.
Big and fancy.
啮齿动物有味道.可以
Rodent's got taste. Okay.
呵呵.几乎让我想变得可爱.
Huh. Almost makes me want to be cute.
果酱：他们说经验是最好的老师.
MARMALADE: They say experience is the best teacher.
他们错了.
And they are wrong.
我是.
I am.
早上好，善良的学生们.
Good morning, students of goodness.
欢迎来到你余生最美好的第一天.
And welcome to the first day of the rest of your best life.
一个巨大的屁股.
A giant butt.
嗯？
Huh?
不是屁股.
Uh, it's-it's not a butt.
这是一盏灯的形状
It's a lamp in the shape of
爱陨石坑陨石，我最伟大的...
the Love Crater Meteorite, my greatest...
-我想知道这是谁的屁股-（鲨鱼喘息）-狼：嗯...
-I wonder whose butt it is. -(Shark gasps) -WOLF: Uh...
再一次，它不是屁股.非常感谢.
Once again, it's not a butt. Thank you.
这是一颗心.现在，正如我所说...
It's a heart. Now, as I was saying...
-那它为什么有脸颊-（嘘）-闭嘴！
-Then why does it have cheeks? -(shushing) -Shut it!
什么我从没见过有双颊的心.
What? I've never seen a heart with cheeks.
（嘲笑）这不是...
(scoffs) It's not a...
-战利品-不是屁股！不是屁股！
-Booty! -It's not a butt! Not a butt!
他知道屁股是什么吗？
Does he know what a butt is?
（清了清嗓子）正如我刚才所说，
(clears throat) As I was saying,
在外面，你们五个是反派，
on the outside, the five of you are villains,
捕食者，无情的反社会者.
predators, remorseless sociopaths.
哦，别说了.你让我脸红了.
Oh, stop. You're making me blush.
但里面有一朵花--
But inside, there's a flower--
善良之花——当它绽放的时候
the flower of goodness-- and when it blooms
你会感觉到那种积极的刺激
and you feel that tingle of positivity
辐射穿过你的身体，
radiating through your body,
你会想一直感受到的.
you're going to want to feel it all the time.
所以我们要去刺激一下？
So we're going for a tingle?
没有刺痛感.
Not any tingle.
善良的刺痛，你会感觉到
The tingle of goodness, which you'll feel
在我最先进的共享实验室里.
in my state-of-the-art Sharing Laboratory.
好的，斯内克先生，我来推你一下.
Okay, Mr. Snake, I'm going to give you a Push Pop.
太棒了帮我推一下！
Great! Push Pop just for me!
-不，分享-为什么？
-No, to share. -Why?
从根本上说，
Well, on a fundamental level,
这是为了满足别人的需求
it's about putting someone else's needs
-领先于你自己-（咯咯笑）
-ahead of your own. -(chuckling)
哦，不，不可能.
Oh, no. No way.
蛇
Snake.
（呻吟）好吧，好吧.
(groans) All right, all right.
这味道会特别甜，
This is going to taste extra sweet,
因为我知道你有多想要它.
'cause I know how bad you want it.
（呻吟）
(groaning)
请给我开门.啊...
Pop me, please. Ah...
（呻吟）
(groaning)
不.笨蛋.
Nope. Sucker.
-就这样-（喘息）
-That's it! -(gasps)
-我会教你分享-（尖叫声）
-I'll teach you to share! -(screams)
（喘息）
(all gasp)
我喜欢分享.很好吃.嗯.
Mm, I like sharing. It's yummy. Mm.
蛇（回声）：完全值得.
SNAKE (echoing): Totally worth it.
太可怕了.
Well, that's terrifying.
让我们试试更简单的.
Let's try something simpler.
一个好人总是注意的
A good person always pays attention
满足他人的需求.
to the needs of others.
现在，这里有一位慈祥体弱的奶奶.
Now, here's a kindly, frail grandma.
（其他人大笑）
(others laughing)
食人鱼先生，帮奶奶过马路.
Mr. Piranha, help grandma across the street.
（嘲笑）当然，当然，当然.我一直都这么做.
(scoffs) Sure, sure, sure. I do this all the time.
-给你，女士-（其他人大笑）
-Here you go, ma'am. -(others laughing)
他肯定会搞砸的.
Oh, he is totally gonna blow it.
那是什么？你说什么
What was that? What did you say
-你觉得我做不到-（狼蛛笑）
-You think I can't do this? -(Tarantula laughing)
-不，不，不，食人鱼-（卡车喇叭鸣响）
-No, no, no, Piranha! -(truck horn blares)
（狼尖叫、呻吟）
(Wolf screams, groans)
也许更简单？
Maybe simpler?
（猫喵喵叫）
(cat meowing)
嘿，看.这是一只卡在树上的猫.
Hey, look. It's a cat stuck in a tree.
再简单不过了.
It doesn't get much simpler than that.
那么，在这种情况下呢
Now, what in this scenario
会让你感到刺痛吗？
would give you that good tingle?
吃了吗？
Eating it?
这就是为什么我总是随身携带两片面包.
This is why I always carry two pieces of bread with me.
不
No.
我想让你...
I want you to s...
-打它-剥皮？
-Smack it. -Skin it?
-刺伤它-煎一下-唱给它听？
-Stab it. -Sauté it. -Sing to it?
省省吧.我要你说...
Save it. I want you to sa...
这很明显...太明显了...我要你保存它.
That's obv... It's so obvi... I want you to save it.
大家：哦！
ALL: Oh!
-对，对-对，对，对.当然
-Right, right. -Right, right, right. Sure.
-来，凯蒂，凯蒂，凯蒂-（咆哮）
-Here, kitty, kitty, kitty. -(growling)
（喵喵）
(meows)
哇，那只猫显然有缺陷.
Whoa, that cat is obviously defective.
你怎么了？
What is wrong with you?
你会让它心脏病发作.
You're gonna give it a heart attack.
（嘲笑）我来处理.
(scoffs) I'll handle this.
-怎么了，爸爸-（嚎叫）
-What's up, papa! -(yowls)
（狼咕噜）
(Wolf grunts)
（尖叫）把他从我脸上弄下来！他在我脸上！
(screams) Get him off my face! He's on my face!
不，不，不，不，不，听着！你在干什么？
No, no, no, no, no, listen! Wh-What are you doing?
（猫叫）
(cat yowling)
（狼呻吟）
(Wolf groans)
可以请问你擅长什么？
Okay. What, may I ask, are you good at?
偷东西.
Stealing stuff.
哦，是的，我们很擅长.
Oh, yeah, we're great at that.
-抢劫-盗窃罪.
-Robbery. -Larceny.
-电报诈骗-勒索.
-Wire fraud. -Extortion.
-逃税-抢劫.
-Tax evasion. -Heists.
-狼蛛：邮件诈骗-等待你说是抢劫？
-TARANTULA: Mail fraud. -Wait. Heists, you say?
那是...是的，这是我们的特色菜.
Well, that's... yeah, that's kind of our specialty.
我可能有个主意.
I might just have an idea.
（吟诵）：解放猪！放了猪！
(chanting): Free the pigs! Free the pigs!
那是一个动物测试实验室.
That is an animal testing lab.
20万只无助的豚鼠，
Within, 200,000 helpless guinea pigs,
所有这些都被虐待狂科学家戳戳戳.
all being poked and prodded by sadistic scientists.
你说豚鼠？
Guinea pigs, you say?
蛇
Snake.
我要你去救他们.
I want you to rescue them.
但这是一次永久的抢劫，
But this is a heist for good,
所以我带了更友好的衣服给你穿.
so I brought something more friendly for you to wear.
-（轮胎吱吱声）-再见.
-(tires squeal) -Bye.
好吧，我们的街头信誉就这样消失了.
Well, there goes our street cred.
至少很舒服.
At least it's comfy.
沃尔夫：好吧，我们需要转移那个科学家的注意力.
WOLF: All right, we need to distract that scientist.
-Shark，你起来了-收到.
-Shark, you're up. -Copy that.
可以我们需要一根绳子和一个钩子.
Okay. We're gonna need a rope and a hook.
-我有这个-其他人：什么？
-I got this one. -OTHERS: What?
你是志愿者吗？
You're volunteering?
你从来没有自愿做过任何事.
You've never volunteered for anything.
当然有.马上
Sure, I did. Right now.
-呃-把我扔上去.吉迪亚普！
-Uh... -Throw me up there. Giddyap!
-真的吗-是的.
-Really? -Yep.
我99%相信你能做到.
I'm 99% sure you can make it.
-好的-来吧！
-Okay. -Let's do it!
嘿，儿子.
Hey there, son.
爸爸
Dad?
我知道你有一份重要的工作，
I know you've got an important job,
但我希望你还有时间跟你老爸聊聊.
but I hope you still have time for a catch with your old man.
-（喘息）-（蛇呻吟）
-(gasps) -(Snake groans)
-嘿，孩子-嗯-96%确定.
-Hey, kiddo. -Huh? -SNAKE: 96% sure.
你永远是我特别的男孩.
You'll always be my special boy.
-啊-（蛇呻吟）
-Aw. -(Snake groans)
大概90%.
SNAKE: Maybe 90%.
我一生都在等待这一刻.
I've been waiting my entire life for this moment.
-蛇（呻吟）：我不知道-可以现在，继续.
-SNAKE (groans): I don't know. -Okay. Now, go long.
哦，孩子，哦，孩子，哦，孩子！
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy!
谢谢你，爸爸！（笑）
Thank you, Daddy! (laughs)
（呻吟）50...今天是星期几？
(groans) 50... What day is it?
我是谁？
Who am I?
果酱：对.豚鼠被锁上了
MARMALADE: Right. The guinea pigs are locked
在一扇三英尺厚的钢门后面.
behind a three-foot-thick steel door.
只有通过通风口才能进去.
The only way in is through the vents.
我得到了它.
I got it.
Upsy daisy.*通过过滤器和通风口*
Upsy-daisy. * Over the filters and through the vents *
我从未见过他如此爽朗.
I have never seen him so chipper.
他一直在冥想吗？
Has he been meditating?
*到天竺鼠之地我们*
* To Guinea Pig Land we... *
（大叫）
(yells)
（呻吟）
(groans)
-（咕噜咕噜）-（豚鼠叽叽喳喳）
-(slurping) -(guinea pigs chittering)
哦
Oh.
（耳语）：蛇攻击.
(whispers): Snake attack.
哦嘿，看，我是Marmalade教授.
Oh. Hey, look, it's Professor Marmalade.
是的，没错.是我.
Yes, that's right. It's me.
救援已经到来.
Help has arrived.
把你的眼睛盯着那扇门.
Just keep your eyes glued to that door.
蛇来吧，蛇.开门.
Snake. Come on, Snake. Open up.
放松
Relax.
这些门很复杂.
These doors are complicated.
-狼蛛：你在开玩笑吗-（咯咯笑）
-TARANTULA: Are you kidding me? -(chuckles)
你以为你在干什么？
What do you think you're doing?
我们应该拯救它们，而不是吃掉它们.
We're supposed to save them, not eat them.
我得说他们去了一个更好的地方.
Well, I'd say they've gone to a better place.
（打嗝，咯咯笑）
(belches, chuckles)
好了，就这样.
All right, that's it.
-吐出来-嘿
-Spit them out. -Hey.
嘿！
(yells) Hey!
不管你喜不喜欢我们都会救你的.
We gonna save you whether you like it or not.
我们在救你，你们这些蠢货.
We're saving you, you stupid hair balls.
不是那扇门.另一扇门.
Not that door. The other door.
嘿，嘿.（咕哝）
Hey, hey. (grunts)
哇！
Whoa!
随时可以.
Any second.
（喘息）
(gasps)
（人们尖叫）
(people screaming)
-（豚鼠尖叫）-（咕噜声）
-(guinea pigs squeaking) -(grunts)
（人们喘着粗气）
(people gasping)
这不是它看起来的样子.
It-it's not what it looks like.
（警报声）
(alarm blaring)
（豚鼠尖叫声）
(guinea pig squeaks)
黛安：侵入、入室盗窃、混乱，
DIANE: Trespassing, burglary, mayhem,
用致命的爬行动物袭击？
assault with a deadly reptile?
好像那些可怜的啮齿动物
As if those poor rodents
经历的还不够.
haven't been through enough already.
不，黛安，求你了.
No, Diane, please.
（叹息）好的.
(sighs) Okay.
对不起，教授，我要给主任打电话.
I'm sorry, Professor, but I'm calling the chief.
请来吧
Please. Come on.
黛安：这个实验结束了.
DIANE: This experiment is over.
果酱：实验需要时间.
MARMALADE: Experiments take time.
你忍不住？
You couldn't help yourself?
所以我有点软弱.起诉我.
So I had a moment of weakness. Sue me.
这在监狱里很难做到.
That's gonna be difficult to do from prison.
伙计们，我们现在该怎么办？
Guys, what do we do now?
是时候发起魅力攻势了.
Hmm. Time to launch a charm offensive.
哦，是的.完整的克鲁尼.
Oh, yeah. The full Clooney.
总督女士.
Madam Governor.
黛安.
Diane.
别耍我，狼.
Do not Clooney me, Wolf.
哦，我明白了.你觉得我还是个坏人，
Oh, I see what's going on. You think I'm still a Bad Guy,
试图欺骗我的自由之路.
trying to bamboozle my way to freedom.
但我们变了.
But we've changed.
善良之花正在遍地开花.
That flower of goodness is blossoming all over the place.
（叹气）你不厌倦撒谎吗？
(sighs) Don't you ever get tired of lying?
（咯咯笑）：不.
(chuckling): No.
我是说...（结结巴巴地）软糖.
I mean... (stammers) Fudge.
那是...那是个诡计问题，对吧？
That was... that was a trick question, right?
（叹息）我给了你一个机会--
(sighs) I gave you an opportunity--
向全世界展示的机会
a chance to show the world
你不仅仅是一个可怕的刻板印象--
that you're more than just a scary stereotype--
但你太骄傲了
but you're too proud
或者太没勇气利用它.
or too gutless to take advantage of it.
胆小鬼？我没有勇气？
Gutless? I'm gutless?
（笑）：哦.
(chuckles): Oh.
对不起，我们见过面吗？
I'm sorry, have we met?
我是每个故事的反派.
I'm the villain of every story.
在被证明无罪之前是有罪的.
Guilty until proven innocent.
即使我们奇迹般地改变了，
Even if by some miracle we did change,
谁会相信我们？
who's gonna believe us, huh?
你当然不知道这件事，
Of course you wouldn't know anything about that,
穿上你的完美女装.
with your Little Miss Perfect power suits.
是这样吗？
Is that so?
等等.
Wait a second.
你做了什么...你怎么...
What did... How did you...
狼和狐狸没什么不同.
A wolf and a fox are not so different.
也许他们会相信你，也许他们不会，
Maybe they will believe you, maybe they won't,
但这无关紧要.
but it doesn't matter.
不要为他们这么做.为你做吧.
Don't do it for them. Do it for you.
这是一个写自己故事的机会.
This is a chance to write your own story.
为你和你的朋友找到更好的生活.
To find a better life for you and your friends.
拜托，你会失去什么？
Come on, what have you got to lose?
我不知道.我的尊严？
I don't know. My dignity?
是的，那艘船已经开航了.
Yeah, well, that ship has already sailed.
信不信由你，我支持你，沃尔夫.
Believe it or not, I'm rooting for you, Wolf.
你不给局长打电话了？
So you're not gonna call the chief?
-晚会上见-（发动机起动）
-I'll see you at the gala. -(engine starts)
（猫在远处喵喵叫）
(cat meows in distance)
（喵喵继续）
(meowing continues)
（喵喵）
(meows)
我想我们的开始不太好.
I think we got off to a bad start.
名字叫沃尔夫.
The name's Wolf.
（呜咽）
(whimpers)
是的.（叹息）
Yep. (sighs)
我知道很多.
I get that a lot.
第一印象等等.
First impressions and all.
（呜咽）
(whimpers)
（喵喵叫）
(meows, yowls)
不，不，不，不（呜咽）
No, no, no, no. (whimpers)
（喘息）
(panting)
（叹息）
(sighs)
没关系.没关系.
Uh, it's okay. It's okay.
我不会伤害你的.我知道你很害怕.
I'm not gonna hurt you. I know you're scared.
如果我是你，我也会的.
I would be, too, if I were you.
给我一个机会.
Just give me a chance.
（轻轻地喵喵叫）
(meows quietly)
事实上，我们有很多共同点.
Truth is we actually have a lot in common.
不要告诉任何人，
Don't tell anyone,
但我喜欢一点点抓伤
but I love a little scratch
就在我耳朵后面.
on the spot behind my ears.
你知道，就在那里.
You know, right there.
最好的.
The best.
（喵喵）
(meows)
来吧，基蒂.
Come on, kitty.
（嗅嗅）
(sniffing)
（喵喵、咕噜）
(meows, purrs)
-**-（咕噜声）
-* * -(purring)
-对.谁是一只好猫-（喵喵）
-Yeah. Who's a good kitty? -(meows)
-谁是一只好猫-狼蛛：嗯，狼？
-Who's a good kitty? -TARANTULA: Uh, Wolf?
你救了他？
Um, you saved him?
果酱：是的！
MARMALADE: Yes!
（咯咯笑）：是的.它起作用了.
(chuckling): Yes. It's working.
你拍的？
You-you filmed that?
是的，他们开始喜欢你了.
Yes, and they're starting to like you.
鲨鱼（咯咯笑）：是啊！
SHARK (chuckling): Yeah!
-好吧-（呜呜声）
-All right! -(whooping)
这可能就足够了
This might just be enough
为了在晚会上赢得客人.
to win over the guests at the gala.
-现在我们在说话-是的-好吧
-Now we're talking! -Yes! -All right!
狼蛛：是的，我们做到了！好吧
TARANTULA: Yeah, we did it! All right!
果酱：嗯，狼？
MARMALADE: Uh, Wolf?
我必须说，你真的转过了一个弯.
I must say, you've really turned a corner.
-你真的明白了-真正地
-You're really getting it. -Really?
-谢谢-（喵喵）
-Oh, uh, thanks. -(meows)
现在，我是认真的.
Now, I mean it.
我可以从头到尾看到它.
And I can see it from tip to tail.
真遗憾，你得背这么多行李.
It's just a shame that you have to carry all that baggage.
你在说什么...你是说那些家伙？
What are you talk... You mean the guys?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你有很大的潜力，狼，
MARMALADE: You have great potential, Wolf,
但在某个时刻，你必须做出选择
but at some point, you're going to have to choose
在你的朋友或美好生活之间.
between your friends or the good life.
（打鼾）
(snoring)
嘿你还醒着吗？
Hey. You still awake?
（猫叫）
(cat meows)
你把猫带进来了？
You-you brought the cat in?
（笑）：是的.是的，是的.
(chuckling): Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
我只是...我只是把它留着以后用.
I'm just... I'm just saving it up for later.
为什么？怎么了？
Why? What's up?
我只是有点担心，
I was just getting a little worried,
既然你成了...
since you've kind of become a...
-成为什么-（咕噜声）
-Become a what? -(purring)
你知道，老师的宠儿.
You know, teacher's pet.
吃果酱会很舒服.
Getting all cozy with Marmalade.
你摇尾巴什么的.
Your tail wagging and everything.
嗯，是的，因为它必须是可信的.
Well, yeah, because it has to be believable.
嗯哼.是的，我想是的.
Uh-huh. Yeah, I guess so.
只要这都是计划的一部分.
As long as it's all part of the plan.
这都是计划的一部分，不是吗？
It is all part of the plan, isn't it?
斯内克，老兄，是谁先计划的？
Snake, buddy, who made the plan to begin with?
是的.
You did.
所以我是最坚持计划的人，对吗？
So I'm the one who sticks to the plan the most, right?
是啊，莉...嗯，是的，好吧...
Yeah, ri... Uh, yeah, ok...
我想这是有道理的.
I guess that makes sense, yeah.
但如果计划要改变，
But if the plan were ever to change,
你会告诉我的，对吧？
you'd-you'd tell me, right?
我向你保证.
You have my word.
变坏...
Go bad...
或者回家.
Or go home.
-嘿，斯内克-是吗-（咕噜声）
-Hey, Snake. -Yeah? -(purring)
你想过会是什么样子吗？
You ever wonder what it'd be like?
世界爱我们而不是害怕我们？
The world loving us instead of being scared of us?
你曾经...你想过吗？
You ever... you ever think about that?
爱我们？
Loving us?
（笑）是的，对.
(chuckles) Yeah, right.
我不会浪费时间去想事情
I don't waste time thinking about stuff
那永远不会发生.
that's never gonna happen.
（叹气）我等不及事情恢复正常了.
(sighs) I can't wait for things to get back to normal.
是 啊恢复正常，恢复正常.
Yeah. Back to normal, back to normal.
（叹息）
(sighs)
（戏剧性新闻主题剧）
(dramatic news theme plays)
怎么了？我们就在眼前
What up? We are just moments away
来自Marmalade教授的慈善晚会，
from Professor Marmalade's Gala for Goodness,
传说中的爱情陨石坑
where the legendary Love Crater Meteorite
将首次展出.
will be on display for the first time ever.
但每个人都在谈论什么呢
But what everyone is really buzzing about
是坏人，他们的心脏融化救援视频
is the Bad Guys, whose heart-melting rescue video
让它们一夜之间引起了轰动.
has made them an overnight viral sensation.
好了，伙计们，这是个大问题.
All right, guys, this is the big one.
金色海豚
The Golden Dolphin
在一个钛壳里
is inside a titanium case
由随机生成的五位数代码控制，
controlled by a randomly generated five-digit code,
确保安全的代码
a code kept safe and secure
在一个手铐着警察局长的公文包里.
inside a briefcase handcuffed to the chief of police.
食人鱼：她不是在胡闹.
PIRANHA: She's not messing around.
WOLF:代码只能通过
WOLF: The code is only accessible with
-她的授权指纹-把这个交给我吧.
-her authorized fingerprints. -SNAKE: Leave that to me.
狼：当蛇得到密码时，
WOLF: While Snake gets the code,
鲨鱼会保护假海豚.
Shark will secure the fake Dolphin.
鲨鱼：我喜欢这声音.
SHARK: I like the sound of that.
沃尔夫：与此同时，我们其他人在安装电路干扰器.
WOLF: Meanwhile, the rest of us plant circuit jammers.
狼蛛：允许我侵入电网.
TARANTULA: Allowing me to hack into the power grid.
晚上结束时，我们向教授敬酒，
WOLF: At the end of the night, we toast the professor,
“废话废话废话，废话废话废话”
"Blah-blah-blah, yada yada,"
当我说“果酱”的时候，灯就熄灭了，
and when I say "Marmalade," lights go out,
我们只有四秒钟的时间行动.
and we'll have exactly four seconds to make our move.
斯内克：那个老开关.
SNAKE: The old switcheroo.
狼：酋长把果酱递给假海豚，
WOLF: Chief hands Marmalade the fake Dolphin,
我们得到了赦免，掌声，掌声，退出舞台，
we get our pardon, applause, applause, exit stage right,
当他们意识到发生了什么时...
and by the time they realize what happened...
（通过扬声器）：再见，笨蛋！
(over speakers): So long, suckers!
...我们将驶向日落，
...we'll be driving off into the sunset,
遗产得到巩固.
legacy cemented.
-（笑声）-食人鱼：很好.
-(laughter) -PIRANHA: Nice.
我得把它交给你，伙计.
Got to hand it to you, buddy.
你真是个艺术家.
You're a real artist.
好了，伙计们，就是这样.
Well, Good Guys, this is it.
祝你好运.
Good luck out there.
记住，今晚所有的眼睛都会盯着你，而不是我.
Remember, all eyes will be on you tonight, not me.
朋友们，见见好人！
Friends, meet the Good Guys!
（欢呼声）
(cheering)
这不一样.
Uh, this is different.
-这是恶作剧吗-那是什么声音？
-Is this a prank? -What's that sound?
像尖叫但不害怕.
Like screaming but not terrified.
好了，伙计们，我们...我们混在一起吧.
All right, guys, let's, uh... let's mingle.
现在是犯罪时间，宝贝.
It's crime time, baby.
*送我去月球*
* Fly me to the moon *
*让我在群星中嬉戏*
* And let me play among the stars *
-嗯-男：好了.
-Hmm? -MAN: There you go.
*让我看看春天是什么样子*
* Let me see what spring is like *
*在木星和火星上*
* On Jupiter and Mars *
*换句话说*
* In other words... *
好吧，假海豚，假海豚，假海豚.
Okay, fake Dolphin, fake Dolphin, fake Dolphin.
答对 了
Bingo.
-鲨鱼先生，鲨鱼先生-哦！
-Mr. Shark, Mr. Shark! -Ooh!
鲨鱼真的能闻到一英里外的血吗？
Is it true sharks can smell blood a mile away?
什么不，这太奇怪了.
What? No. That's freaky.
*用歌声填满我的心*
* Fill my heart with song *
（蛇咯咯地笑）
(Snake chuckling)
*让我永远歌唱*
* And let me sing forevermore... *
-哦，狼先生！沃尔夫先生-（笑）：嘿.哇.
-Oh, Mr. Wolf! Mr. Wolf! -(chuckling): Hey. Whoa.
很高兴见到你.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
-这是我的荣幸-我喜欢你的视频.
-Pleasure is all mine. -I loved your video.
我能给我的孩子们照张相吗？
Can I get a picture for my kids?
等一下，伙计们.让我...让我，呃...
Uh, hey, just a minute, guys. Let me... let me, uh...
我有...我马上回来.
I got... I'll be right back.
*换句话说，我爱你*
* In other words, I love you... *
好了，沃尔夫，你在忙什么？
Okay, Wolf, what are you up to?
对，像这样的罪犯，
Yeah, with criminals like this,
你必须狡猾、微妙、隐形.
you got to be crafty, subtle, invisible.
然后当他们放松警惕的时候...
And then the moment they let their guard down...
-哇-（呻吟）
-whammo! -(groans)
你必须跳出陷阱！
You gotta spring the trap!
（咯咯笑）：总是领先一步.
(chuckling): Always one step ahead.
我想我已经赚了一杯补水.
I think I've earned a tonic water.
把它放在有趣的杯子里，嗯？
Put it in a fun glass, huh?
哦美好的
Oh! Nice.
-（蛇呻吟）-（喘息）
-(Snake groans) -(gasps)
-哦，不.-（喘息）
-Oh, no. -(gasps)
嘿（口吃）
Hey. (stammers)
（喘息）
(gasps)
-（紧张地笑了起来）-嘿.
-(chuckles nervously) -Hey.
这是正确的.
That's right.
-被吓倒-（蛇呻吟）
-Be intimidated. -(Snake groans)
嗯.
Mm.
不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不！
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
-*看...看着我*-（客人喃喃地说）
-* Look... at me * -(guests murmuring)
-什么-隐马尔可夫模型？
-What? -Hmm?
（呻吟）
(groans)
*告诉我...你看*
* Tell me what... you see *
*我好吗...还是坏*
* Am I good... or bad? *
（紧张地咯咯笑）
(chuckles nervously)
（抓取记录）
(record scratching)
*你不要评判...这么快*
* Don't you judge... so fast *
（欢呼声）
(cheering)
*嘿，嘿，嘿，我知道你以为你了解我*
* Hey, hey, hey, I know you think you know me *
*你已经得出了自己的结论*
* You've made your own conclusion *
*你觉得我看起来很吓人*
* You think that I look scary *
（呻吟）
(groans)
*那是你自己的错觉*
* Well, that's your own delusion *
*听我说*
* Listen when I tell you *
*这不仅仅是表面上的*
* There's more than meets the eye *
-*所以仔细看一看*-（呻吟）
-* So take a closer look * -(groans)
*找到一个真正的好人*
* To find a real good guy *
*我们不是坏人*
* We're not the Bad Guys... *
戴安：沃尔夫先生.
DIANE: Mr. Wolf.
黛安.是啊，真是个惊喜.
Diane. Yeah, what a surprise.
如果我不知道的话，
You know, if I didn't know better,
我以为你在躲避我.
I'd think that you were avoiding me.
避开你？
Avoiding you?
我为什么要这么做？
Wh-Why would I do that?
可以
Okay.
但我不得不说，我有点失望.
But I have to say, I'm a little disappointed.
我希望你能邀请我跳舞.
I was hoping you were gonna ask me to dance.
哦
Oh.
*趴在地板上*
* Get up on the floor *
*我们今晚会很好的*
* We're gonna be good tonight *
*想让你感觉良好吗*
* Wanna get you feeling right *
*我们今晚会很好的*
* We're gonna be good tonight *
*我们是好人，好人*
* We're the Good, Good Guys *
*我们今晚会很好的*
* We're gonna be good tonight *
*想让你感觉良好吗*
* Wanna get you feeling right *
*我们今晚会很好的*
* We're gonna be good tonight *
*我们是好人，好人*
* We're the Good, Good Guys *
*来吧！哦*
* Come on! Ooh... *
我懂了.你丢了羊皮.
I see. You lost the sheep's clothing.
是 啊我觉得是时候穿上自己的皮草了.
Yeah. Figured it was time I got comfortable in my own fur.
食人鱼：如果你在这里感觉很好...
PIRANHA: If you're feeling good in here...
我说，如果你在这里感觉良好...
I said, if you're feeling good in here...
（笑声）
(laughter)
*哦，是的*
* Oh, yeah *
我想我喜欢新的你.
I think I like the new you.
好吧，那就是我们两个人.
Well, that makes two of us.
*我们都在这里度过美好时光*
* We're all here to have a good, good time *
*让节奏打动你，打开你的心扉*
* Let the rhythm move you and open up your mind *
*下次你在你家附近看到我*
* Next time you see me in your neighborhood *
*你难道不认为我在干坏事吗*
* Don't you be thinking that I'm up to no good *
*我只想你给我一个机会*
* I just want you to give me a chance *
*我知道你的身体很想跳舞*
* I know your body really wants to dance *
*所以请留下你的判断*
* So leave your judgments... *
拿出雨伞，因为正在下雨.
Break out the umbrellas, because it's raining money.
都是因为我不敢相信我会这么说--
All because of-- I can't even believe I'm saying this--
都是因为坏人.
all because of the Bad Guys.
*想让你感觉良好吗*
* Wanna get you feeling right *
*我们今晚会很好的*
* We're gonna be good tonight *
*我们是好人，好人*
* We're the Good, Good Guys *
*我们今晚会很好的*
* We're gonna be good tonight *
*想让你感觉良好吗*
* Wanna get you feeling right *
*我们今晚会很好的*
* We're gonna be good tonight *
*我们是好人，好人，哇*
* We're the Good, Good Guys, whoo... *
那么，感觉如何
So, how does it feel
让每个人都不害怕你的改变？
to have everyone not fear you for a change?
-（喘息）-（音乐继续低沉）
-(panting) -(music continues muffled)
（低沉的欢呼声）
(muffled cheering)
感觉很好.
It feels good.
真的很好.
Real good.
黛安...
Diane...
（轻轻地喘息）
(gasps softly)
它属于你.
It belongs to you.
（音乐声）
(music unmuffles)
-*我们今晚会很好的*
-* We're gonna be good tonight * -* Uh-huh *
*我们今晚会很好的*
* We're gonna be good tonight *
*一，二，三，我们是好人*
* Ah, one, two, three, we're the Good, Good Guys *
-*我们今晚会过得很好的*
-* We're gonna be good tonight * -* So good *
*会让你感觉良好的*
* Gonna get you feeling right *
-*我们今晚会过得很好的*
-* We're gonna be good tonight * -* So good *
*我们是好人，好人*
* We're the Good, Good Guys *
*哦，是的*
* Oh, yeah... *
-（歌曲结束）-（欢呼和掌声）
-(song ends) -(cheering and applause)
（烟花鸣笛和爆炸声）
(sound of fireworks whistling and exploding)
非常感谢.谢谢你，沃尔夫先生.
Thank you. Thank you, Mr. Wolf.
正如你所知，今晚筹集的资金
As you know, the money raised tonight
将于明天送到学校和医院
will be delivered tomorrow to schools, hospitals
以及全市其他有价值的事业.
and other worthy causes across the city.
（欢呼声）
(cheering)
UH（清嗓子）
Uh... (clears throat)
我只想花点时间来认识一下
I just want to take a moment to recognize
对我们的新观点负责的人.
the one responsible for our new outlook.
我们杰出的导师，
Our brilliant mentor,
-启蒙的典范-去做吧-来吧
-a paragon of enlightenment... -Do it. -Come on.
...唯一的教授...
...the one and only Professor...
-狼蛛：狼，去吧-狼：...教授...
-TARANTULA: Wolf, do it. -WOLF: ...uh, Professor...
（嘶嘶声）
(hisses)
...嗯...
...um...
...果酱教授！
...Professor Marmalade!
（欢呼声）
(cheering)
警长，我能为您效劳吗？
Chief, may I do the honors?
这不是计划.
That's not the plan.
发生了什么事？
What is happening?
他变得无赖了.
He's gone rogue.
交易就是交易.
A deal's a deal.
凭借赋予我的权力，这是我的荣幸
By the power vested in me, it is a pleasure
给坏人一个完整的标准...
to grant the Bad Guys a full par...
（客人们喘着气，喃喃地说）
(guests gasping, murmuring)
-真奇怪-陨石不见了！
-That was weird. -MAN: The meteorite is gone!
有人偷了！
Somebody stole it!
-（酋长呻吟）-酋长.
-(chief groans) -Chief.
-狼.（咆哮）-来吧.
-Wolf. (growls) -Come on.
你不可能认为是我们干的.
You can't possibly think that we did this.
（通过扬声器）：再见，笨蛋！
(over speakers): So long, suckers!
跑
Run!
抓住他们！
Get them!
（喧闹）
(clamoring)
UH（咯咯笑）
Uh... (chuckles)
-（喘息）-（警官们咕哝着）
-(panting) -(officers grunting)
在这里在这里
Here. Here.
-你在干什么-我要把一切都还给你.
-What are you doing? -I'm giving it all back.
嗯？
Huh?
-（吵闹声）-对不起.
-(clamoring) -Excuse me.
（喘息、咕哝）
(panting, grunting)
-后面发生了什么-我做不到.
-What happened back there? -I couldn't do it.
你不能做是什么意思？
What do you mean, you couldn't do it?
-我只是...我-不
-I-I-I just... I... -No!
-我不跑-警察：小屋，小屋，小屋...
-I do not run. -OFFICERS: Hut, hut, hut...
我不是这样滚的.
That is not how I roll.
食人鱼，不要做任何疯狂的事.
Piranha, don't do anything crazy.
（笑）
(laughing)
疯狂是我在派对上带来的，奇科.
Crazy is what I bring to the party, chico.
（鲨鱼呻吟）
(Shark groans)
嘿，你搞错了.
Hey, you're making a mistake.
不是我们干的.
We didn't do it.
我知道我们总是这么说，
I know we always say that,
但这次是真的.
but this time it's actually true.
啦啦啦啦.听不见.
A-la-la-la-la. Can't hear you.
-有罪，有罪，有罪-和果酱谈谈.
-Guilty, guilty, guilty. -Talk to Marmalade.
我们现在真的很好.他会告诉你的.
We're really good now. He'll tell you.
教授
Professor!
今晚的标题是：改变是不可能的.
Tonight's headline: Change is impossible.
你应该根据封面来判断一本书，
You should always judge a book by its cover,
所有的刻板印象都得到了肯定.
and all stereotypes have been affirmed.
橘子酱：停下来，看在上帝的份上！
MARMALADE: Stop, for goodness' sake!
让我和他们谈谈.
Let me speak to them.
我肯定有些误会.
I'm-I'm sure there's been some misunderstanding.
-（门开了）-啊，果酱教授.
-(door opens) -Ah, Professor Marmalade.
你还有五分钟.
You've got five minutes.
这次没有交易.
No deals this time.
你必须帮助我们.
Y-You have to help us.
告诉他们，告诉他们我们没有这么做.
Tell 'em. Tell 'em we didn't do it.
好了，好了.当然不是你干的.
There, there. Of course you didn't do it.
你怎么能？
How could you?
毕竟，你是个好孩子.
After all, you're such a good boy.
你真是个好孩子.
You're such a good boy.
让我脊梁骨颤抖.
That shiver up my spine.
我的小尾巴在摇摆.
The wag in my tiny tail.
逮捕他们！
Arrest them!
如果我们做个小实验呢，黛安？
What if we tried a little experiment, Diane?
如你所知，我为上帝举办的晚会...
As you know, my Gala for Goodness...
蒂芙尼：传说中的爱情陨石坑
TIFFANY: Where the legendary Love Crater Meteorite
将首次展出.
will be on display for the first time ever.
今晚所有的目光都会聚焦在你身上，而不是我.
All eyes will be on you tonight, not me.
你真是个...
WOMAN: You're such a...
果酱：好孩子.
MARMALADE: Good boy.
你
You.
全是你.
It was all you.
你在说什么，狼？
What are you talking about, Wolf?
老太太，金色海豚，
The old lady, the Golden Dolphin,
很好的训练让我们来到这里，
good training-- it was all to get us here,
这样他就能偷走陨石，让我们承担责任.
so he could steal the meteorite and let us take the fall.
哇.哇，什么老太太？
Whoa. Whoa, what old lady?
为什么豚鼠想要陨石呢？
And-and why would a guinea pig want a meteorite anyway?
（橘子酱咯咯笑）
(Marmalade chuckling)
伙计们，他吓到我了.
Uh, guys, he's creeping me out.
等等，什么？发生什么事？
Wait, what? What's going on?
有人把我转过来.
Someone turn me around.
果酱：好吧，好吧.
MARMALADE: Well, well.
所以，你终于明白了.
So, you finally get it.
-等等-什么
-Wait. -What?
你偷了陨石？
You stole the meteorite?
哦，不仅仅是陨石.
Oh, it's not just a meteorite.
我告诉过你们这是个屁股.
I told you guys it's a butt.
不是屁股！
It's not a butt!
（深呼吸）
(takes deep breath)
它是终极的能源.
It's the ultimate power source.
你看，当它来袭时，科学家们发现
You see, when it struck, scientists found that
它发出电磁频率
it emitted an electromagnetic frequency
不像地球上的任何东西.
unlike anything else on Earth.
我要利用它的力量
I'm going to harness its power
完成了世界上最大的抢劫案.
to pull off the greatest heist the world has ever seen.
你应该在有机会的时候吃掉他.
You should've eaten him when you had the chance.
-是的-但为什么是我们？
-Yep. -But why us?
因为你是完美的替罪羊.
Because you're the perfect patsies.
拜托，当人们在字典里查“bad”的时候，
Come on, when people look up "bad" in the dictionary,
他们看到一只可爱的豚鼠了吗？
do they see a sweet, adorable guinea pig?
不，他们看见你了.
No. They see you.
他们永远都会.
And they always will.
好吧，好吧.
Okay, fine.
但你陷害了我们.
But you set us up.
（咯咯笑）：哦，pish pish.
(chuckling): Oh, pish-pish.
说实话，进化让你陷害了.
Let's be honest-- evolution set you up.
但这里的Wolfie真的做到了.
But Wolfie here really clinched it.
你落入了我的每一个陷阱，
You fell for every one of my traps,
从救一个无助的小老太太开始.
starting with saving a helpless little old lady.
沃尔夫，他在说什么？
Wolf, what's he talking about?
果酱：哎呀.
MARMALADE: Whoops.
我说得太多了吗？
Did I say too much?
不管怎样，看起来又一次，
Anyhoo, looks like, yet again,
大灰狼被一只小猪打败了.
the Big Bad Wolf got outsmarted by a little piggy.
你这个小脸蛋！
You little pouchy-cheeked rat!
我要杀了你！听到了吗？
I'll kill you! You hear me?
-你死定了！你是-帮助帮助帮助
-You're dead! You're de... -Help! Help! Help!
大灰狼正在攻击我.
The Big Bad Wolf is attacking me.
哦，现在你永远完了，狼！
Oh, now you are done forever, Wolf!
-（发动机转速）-（警报器鸣叫）
-(engine revs) -(sirens wailing)
-蒂芙尼：教授，教授，
-(Marmalade whimpering) -TIFFANY: Professor, Professor,
有没有想过坏人是怎么对付的
any thoughts on how the Bad Guys managed
在肉眼可见的地方偷走陨石？
to steal the meteorite in plain sight?
好吧，在我脑子里，
Well, off the top of my head,
也许他们以前访问过这个网站
perhaps they accessed the site previously
建立了一个复杂的系统
and set up an intricate system
-隧道和活板门-蒂芙妮：嗯.
-of tunnels and trapdoors... -TIFFANY: Uh-huh.
果酱：...这可能是远程触发的
MARMALADE: ...that could be remotely triggered
把陨石吸到等待区，
to suck the meteorite down into a holding area,
-但我怎么知道呢-蒂芙妮：完全正确.
-but how should I know? -TIFFANY: Totally.
果酱：我是说，他们是精神错乱的主谋，不是我.
MARMALADE: I mean, they're the deranged masterminds, not me.
狼：我要把一切都还给你.
WOLF: I'm giving it all back.
（风啸）
(wind howling)
鲨鱼：真不敢相信我们被双重欺骗了
SHARK: I can't believe we got double-crossed
一只小啮齿动物.
by a tiny rodent.
我们被一只啮齿类动物出卖了好吧，
Oh, we got double-crossed by a rodent all right,
-但是，嗯，一点也不小-什么
-but, uh, not a tiny one. -What?
这应该是我们在骗橘子酱.
This was supposed to be us conning Marmalade.
原来是狼在骗我们.
It turns out it was Wolf conning us.
（干呕）
(retching)
你听上去熟悉吗，沃尔夫？
Does that sound familiar to you, Wolf?
你为什么这么想？
Why-why would you think that?
我不知道，也许是因为你破坏了
Oh, I don't know, maybe because you just sabotaged
这是我们一生中最大的抢劫.
the biggest heist of our lives.
我想你应该向我们解释一下，伙计.
I think you owe us an explanation, buddy.
（叹息）
(sighs)
可以你说得对.
Okay. You're right.
事情就是这样.
This is what happened.
回到博物馆，我刚想偷一位老太太的钱包.
Back in the museum, I just tried to steal an old lady's purse.
-（相机快门捕捉）-经典抓取和抓取.
-(camera shutter snaps) -Classic snatch and grab.
试过了吗？你什么时候开始尝试的
Tried to? Since when do you try
去偷东西而不仅仅是偷？
to steal something and not just steal it?
我正想偷钱包，这时老太太摔倒了...
I was trying to steal the purse when the old lady fell and...
（清了清嗓子）我帮了她一点忙.
(clears throat) I kind of helped her.
-什么-（相机快门捕捉）
-What? -(camera shutter snaps)
我帮了她一把.
I kind of helped her.
-但后来你偷了她的钱包-（相机快门捕捉）
-But then you stole her purse. -(camera shutter snaps)
（笑）：不，我没有.
(chuckling): No, I didn't.
我救了老太太她拥抱了我，
I saved the old lady, and she hugged me,
我摇着尾巴，不知道那是什么，
and my tail wagged, and I didn't know what it was,
但感觉，呃，你知道...好的
but it felt, uh, you know... good.
（鲨鱼、狼蛛和食人鱼喘息）
(Shark, Tarantula and Piranha gasp)
啊.
Ah.
但后来你偷了钱包.
But then you stole the purse.
其他人：不！
OTHERS: No!
我听到猪对你说的话了
You know, I heard what the pig said to you
让我们放松.
about cutting us loose.
等待比如“我们”我们？
Wait. Like, "us" us?
但我从没想过你真的会这么做.
But I never thought you'd actually do it, man.
嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
我永远不会...我想...
I-I would never... I was trying to...
我想给我们找到更好的生活.
I was trying to find us a better life.
我们的生活是完美的，直到你决定毁掉它.
Our life was perfect until you decided to ruin it.
我没有.
I didn't.
你们在晚会上感觉到了.
You guys felt it at the gala.
掌声，欢呼声.
The clapping, the cheering.
我们不仅仅是...而不仅仅是可怕的恶棍.
We were more than... than just scary villains.
他们爱我们.
They loved us.
哦，是吗？如果他们这么爱我们，
Oh, yeah? If they loved us so much,
我们怎么会因为没犯的罪而坐牢？
how come we're in prison for a crime we didn't commit?
你知道吗？我给你这个橘子酱.
You know what? I'll give Marmalade this.
至少他看到了世界的本来面目：
At least he sees the world for what it is:
有些人害怕的地方
a place where some people are scary
有些人很害怕.
and some people are scared.
哦，是吗？
Oh, yeah?
我已经厌倦了害怕.
Well, I'm tired of being scary.
我厌倦了做一个被遗弃的人.
I'm-I'm tired of being an outcast.
也许我不想成为...
Maybe I don't want to be a...
什么坏人？
What? A Bad Guy?
不想再做坏人了吧？
Don't want to be a Bad Guy anymore, huh?
说吧，狼.
Say it, Wolf.
是的，我想是的.
Yeah, I thought so.
还有我们，你一生的朋友？
And us, your lifelong friends?
我们只是在阻止你？
We're just holding you back?
是的，也许你是！
Yeah, maybe you are!
（喘息）
(gasps)
（咆哮）收回！
(snarls) Take it back!
-（喘息）-拿回去！道歉
-(gasping) -Take it back! Apologize!
警卫：嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿！
GUARD: Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
监狱不是打架的地方.
Prison is no place for fighting.
（警卫喊道）
(guard yells)
（呻吟）：告诉他.
(groaning): Tell that to him.
嗯？
Huh?
-（笑）：什么-（警卫喊道）
-(chuckling): What? -(guards yelling)
（咕哝着，喊叫着）
(grunting, yelling)
（快速呼噜）
(grunting rapidly)
（继续咕哝和大喊）
(grunting and yelling continue)
（警卫喊道）
(guard yelling)
-嘘-（咕哝）
-Shh. -(grunts)
（继续咕哝和大喊）
(grunting and yelling continue)
-（嘎吱声）-（咕噜声）
-(crunching) -(grunting)
（尖叫、呜咽）
(screams, whimpers)
卫兵：快跑！
GUARD: Run!
（呻吟）
(groans)
-哦-等等，等等.等等.
-Oh! -W-W-Wait, wait. Ho-Hold on.
（其他人喘着粗气）
(others gasping)
大家：黛安？
ALL: Diane?
但是你怎么知道该怎么做呢
But how do you know how to do
所有的踢踏拳？
all of that kick-kick-punch-punch?
等等，你是那个深红色的爪子？
Wait a sec, you're the Crimson Paw?
狼：囚徒女王，
WOLF: The queen of cons,
特技瑞士军刀.
acrobatic Swiss Army knife.
两次偷了尊邦戈钻石.
Stole the Zumpango diamond twice.
一次是为了赚钱，第二次只是为了好玩.
Once for profit, second time just for fun.
从未被识别，从未被发现.
Never identified, never caught.
（笑）我想我仍然是最好的坏人
(chuckles) Guess I'm still the best bad guy
全世界都见过.
the world has ever seen.
-至少我以前是-（警报声）
-Ugh, at least I used to be. -(alarm blaring)
-（鲨鱼喘息）-狼蛛：嗯？
-(Shark gasps) -TARANTULA: Huh?
（警卫喊道）
(guards yelling)
（大叫）
(yells)
（爆炸声隆隆）
(explosions booming)
不，我还是最好的.
Nope, I'm still the best.
就像骑偷来的自行车.
Just like riding a stolen bicycle.
你有点...哎哟
Oh, uh, you got a little... Ouch.
你为什么要救我们？
Hey, wh-why did you save us anyway?
晚会结束后我知道有些不对劲，
After the gala, I knew something wasn't right,
所以我做了一些调查，那颗流星...
so I did some investigating, and that meteor...
我知道.某种宇宙超级天线的东西.
I know. Some kind of cosmic mega-super-antennae thing.
正当如果通过一系列电离晶体传导，
Right. If conducted through an array of ionized crystals,
它将产生一个巨大的心理动力场
it will generate a massive psychokinetic field
城市的大小.
the size of a city.
天哪.我打断你了吗？
Oh, my gosh. Did I interrupt you?
你要这么说吗？
Were you gonna say that?
呃，我，我，我本想更专业一点，
Uh, I-I-I was gonna be a little more technical,
-但你知道要点了-（咯咯笑）
-but you got the gist of it. -(chuckles)
果酱需要停止，但我一个人做不到.
Marmalade needs to be stopped, but I can't do it alone.
你比任何人都了解他的化合物.
You know his compound better than anyone.
你可以相信我们.
You can count on us.
对吧，伙计们？
Right, guys?
没有“我们”
There is no "us."
我们完了，狼.
We're through, Wolf.
完成.菲尼托.
Done. Finito.
就因为那场小小的争吵？
Because of that little tiff back there?
拜托，伙计，我们就是这么做的.
Come on, man, that's what we do.
你发球，我截击.
You serve, I volley.
那是我们的小舞会.
That's our little dance.
这次不行.
Not this time.
食人鱼？
Piranha?
网？
Webs?
抱歉Wolfie.
Sorry, Wolfie.
（咯咯笑）：鲨鱼.
(chuckling): Shark.
鲨鱼：嗯.
SHARK: Hmm.
狼：嘿.
WOLF: Hey.
伙计们？
Guys?
你想知道我为什么讨厌生日吗，沃尔夫？你…吗？
You want to know why I hate birthdays, Wolf? Do you?
当你长成一条蛇的时候，没有人来参加你的聚会.
When you grow up a snake, nobody shows up to your party.
生日时刻提醒着我们
Birthdays are a constant reminder that out there
我只是一个可怕的，一无是处的怪物.
I'm just a scary, good-for-nothing monster.
是 啊
Yeah.
但没有什么能比得上只有一个人...
But nothing compares to having the one guy...
那个我以为可以信任的人
the one guy I thought I could trust
从背后捅我一刀.
stab me in the back.
来吧，伙计们.我们从这里出去吧.
Come on, guys. Let's get out of here.
（没有音频）
(no audio)
（电爆裂声）
(electrical crackling)
（有节奏的脉动）
(rhythmic pulsing)
这才是真正的坏蛋.
Now, this is what a true bad guy looks like.
（电子音）
(electronic tone)
我们玩得开心点怎么样？
What do you say we have some fun?
（隆隆声）
(rumbling)
（狂笑）
(laughing maniacally)
（爆炸性的嗖嗖声）
(explosive whooshing)
（喘息、咕哝）
(gasps, grunts)
（尖叫声）
(screams)
（闲聊）
(chittering)
（尖叫）
(screaming)
（吱吱嘎吱的闲聊）
(squeaky chittering)
嘿你没事吧？
Hey. You okay?
不，我不好.
No, I'm not okay.
我非常非常不好.
I'm very, very un-okay.
（抱怨）
(grumbles)
刚刚离开我唯一的朋友，
Just left the only friends I have ever had,
那我是什么...（叹息）我在做什么？
so what am I... (sighs) what am I doing?
（叹息）
(sighs)
我知道这不容易，
I know this isn't easy,
把一切抛在脑后.
leaving everything behind.
-是吗-是 啊
-Do you? -Yeah.
我是世界上最好的小偷.
I was the best thief in the world.
快速、无畏、有创造力.
Fast, fearless, inventive.
我只剩下一件东西要偷了.
I just had one thing left to steal.
金色海豚.
The Golden Dolphin.
所以你去追了.
So you went after it.
我不只是去追求它.
I didn't just go after it.
我做到了.
I had it.
还有一条清晰的逃生路线.
And a clear escape route.
但是
But...
最后我只看到了那只狡猾的狐狸
all I saw in the end was the tricky fox
他们总是告诉我我是.
that they always told me I was.
它改变了一切.
It changed everything.
所以现在，与其伤害别人，
So, now, instead of hurting people,
我在帮助他们.（叹息）
I'm helping them. (sighs)
我还是我自己.（咯咯笑）
I'm still me. (chuckles)
我只是站在右边的我.
I'm just me on the right side.
你做得对.
You're doing the right thing.
有一天你的朋友如果他们是真正的朋友，
And someday your friends, if they're real friends,
我想他们会理解的.
I think they'll understand.
现在，来吧，我们进去吧.
Now, come on, let's get inside.
-你看起来像刚从监狱里逃出来-（咯咯笑）
-You look like you just busted out of a prison. -(chuckles)
（两人都喘着粗气）
(both gasp)
（闲聊）
(chitters)
-豚鼠？（喘息）-（屋顶上急促的脚步声）
-Guinea pigs? (gasps) -(footsteps scurrying on roof)
两者都有：果酱.
BOTH: Marmalade.
让我们跳起来.
Let's bounce.
这就是大红爪子的藏身之处.
So this is the hideout of the great Crimson Paw.
-（黛安咯咯笑）-（微波炉发出哔哔声）
-(Diane chuckles) -(microwave beeping)
小吃休息？
Snack break?
好吧，时间很奇怪，但你知道.
Okay, oddly timed, but you do you.
（大叫）
(yells)
自动语音：身份验证.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Identity verified.
-什么-欢迎，黛安.
-What? -Welcome, Diane.
-哇！天哪-（笑）
-Whoa! Holy moly! -(laughing)
（叹息）回家真是太好了.
(sighs) It's so good to be home.
你在开玩笑吧？
Are you kidding me?
激光瞄准拉链？
Laser-sighted zip line?
XM-2400雷达干扰机？不可能.
The XM-2400 radar jammer? No way.
实际上我更喜欢早期的型号.
I actually prefer the earlier model.
同意不同意.
Agree to disagree.
这东西也不错.
Uh, this stuff is nice, too.
（尖叫声）
(screams)
是的，那是喷灯.
Yeah, that's a blowtorch.
而且，不是你的颜色.
Also, not really your color.
（呻吟）
(groans)
好的，果酱.
All righty, Marmalade.
你在干什么，你这个毛茸茸的小怪人？
What are you up to, you fuzzy little weirdo?
我们需要关注这座城市.
We need eyes on the city.
让我们看看是否能破解
Let's see if we can't hack
进入政府的监控卫星.
into the government's surveillance satellite.
但你是州长.你就不能问问吗？
But you're the governor. Couldn't you just ask?
是的，但是...文书工作.
Yeah, but... (splutters) the paperwork.
（黛安咕哝着）
(Diane muttering)
我肯定在这里发现了可疑的活动.
I am definitely picking up on suspicious activity here.
这些是豚鼠的热信号.
Those are guinea pig heat signatures.
果酱似乎在控制它们.
Marmalade seems to be controlling them.
但是做什么呢？
But to do what?
没有明显的目标.
There are no obvious targets.
那是因为他们在移动目标.
That's because they're moving targets.
黛安：（喘息）他的慈善筹款.
DIANE: (gasps) His charity fundraiser.
他要偷他自己名下的钱？
He's gonna steal the money raised in his own name?
这是世界上有史以来最大的抢劫案.
It's the greatest heist the world's ever seen.
卡车里有10亿美元，
$1 billion inside trucks,
在去全市慈善机构的路上.
on their way to charities all over the city.
我们需要切断果酱的联系
We need to cut off Marmalade's communication
和他的豚鼠军队在一起.
with his guinea pig army.
如果没有信号...
If there's no signal...
没有抢劫.
There's no heist.
两个：我们必须偷陨石.
BOTH: We have to steal the meteorite.
很可爱，
That was very cute,
-我们刚才在那里做的事-好吧
-that thing we just did there. -All right.
穿上你的大女孩裤子.我们正在准备.
Put on your big-girl pants. We're gearing up.
我不会接受的.
I wouldn't take that.
那些东西会把你的裤子扯下来.
Those things rip your pants right off.
呵呵.试着穿干净的内衣.
Huh. Try wearing clean underwear.
以防万一.
Just in case.
什么...
Wha...
你偷了我的车？
You stole my car?
尊敬
Respect.
-我们开始吧-（发动机转速、轮胎吱吱声）
-Let's do this. -(engine revs, tires squeal)
-（电梯铃响）-（所有人都喘着粗气）
-(elevator bell dings) -(all gasp)
-不-什么
-No! -What?
我们所有的东西？
All our stuff?
-一切都在哪里-不，不，不，不，不.
-Where is everything? -No, no, no, no, no.
-不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不-我们所有的东西.
-No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no! -All our stuff.
-都没了-我的伪装柜！
-It's all gone. -My disguise closet!
-狼蛛：我的东西呢-（衣架叮当作响）
-TARANTULA: Where's my things? -(hangers clanging)
狼把我们所有的战利品都给了我们.
Wolf gave away all our loot.
我们把它偷走了.
We stole it fair and square.
现在我明白这是什么感觉了
Now I understand what it feels like
把你的东西偷走.（颤抖的呼吸）
to have things stolen from you. (shuddering breaths)
我不喜欢！
I don't like it!
我真的不喜欢！（呜咽）
I really don't like it! (whimpers)
-（呻吟）-（鲨鱼哭泣）
-(groans) -(Shark sobbing)
鲨鱼：我们没有食物.我们没有钱.
SHARK: We got no food. We got no money.
我们没有钱可以用来买食物.
We got no money we could use to buy food.
我们卖不到能赚钱的食物.（咕哝）
No food we can sell for money. (grunts)
我们（抽泣）
We... (sobs)
好吧，好吧，好吧.
All right, okay, okay.
这里，这里.拿去吧.
Here, here. Take it.
别哭了，伙计.
Now, stop crying, buddy.
（叹息）
(sighs)
斯内克，你刚才做了什么？
Um, Snake, what did you just do?
什么我的朋友很伤心.
What? My friend was sad.
我只是在给他加油.
I was just cheering him up.
你你做了一件好事.
You... you did a good thing.
-对我来说-别傻了.
-For me. -Don't be ridiculous.
我只是把你的需要放在我自己的需要之前.
I just put your needs before my own.
-对.你表现得很好-我不是.
-Yeah. You're being good. -I'm not.
我只是为了让鲨鱼开心而做出牺牲.
I was simply making a sacrifice so Shark could be happy.
这就是“好”的实际定义.
That is the actual definition of being good.
斯内克，你，
Snake, you,
我们中最坏的一个，最自私的一个.
the worst one of us, the most selfish.
-恶毒的-可怕的
-Spiteful. -Terrible.
-鬼鬼祟祟的-不诚实的.
-Sneaky. -Dishonest.
-麻木不仁-善于操纵的
-Insensitive. -Manipulative.
-蛇形的-斯坦基.
-Snakelike. -Stanky.
你的意思是？
And your point is?
我认为沃尔夫是对的.
I think Wolf was right.
也许我们不只是可怕的恶棍.
Maybe we could be more than just scary villains.
（喘息）
(gasps)
什么...？
Wh...?
狼蛛：哦，哇.
TARANTULA: Oh, wow.
这是...这是摇摆吗？
Is this... is this wagging?
我们在摇摆.
We're-we're wagging.
（咕哝）
(grunting)
不，不，不！
No, no, no!
我们永远都是坏人！
We'll always be Bad Guys!
（喘息）
(panting)
（电爆裂声）
(electrical crackling)
-（男人尖叫）-（吱吱嘎吱的咯咯声）
-(man yelps) -(squeaky chittering)
（狂笑）
(laughing maniacally)
快点，快点，我的小猪.
Faster, faster, my little pigs.
（欢呼声）
(cheering)
-（砰砰）-（轮胎吱吱作响）
-(thumping) -(tires squeal)
（喘息）
(all gasp)
（闲聊）
(chittering)
（司机尖叫）
(driver screams)
-（呻吟）-（轮胎尖叫）
-(groans) -(tires squeal)
（哭泣）
(crying)
（笑）
(laughing)
（欢呼声）
(cheering)
（咯咯笑）
(chuckles)
-（尖叫）-（司机尖叫）
-(squeaks) -(driver yelps)
（司机尖叫）
(driver screams)
-（司机尖叫）-（轮胎尖叫）
-(drivers scream) -(tires squeal)
（吱吱嘎吱的闲聊）
(squeaky chittering)
-（人们尖叫）-（爆炸声）
-(people screaming) -(explosion booms)
（轮胎吱吱作响）
(tires squeal)
一旦我们偷了陨石，
Once we steal the meteorite,
我们直接报警.
we take it straight to the police.
一切都会被原谅.
And all will be forgiven.
我不知道“全部”，但这只是个开始.
I don't know about "all," but it's a start.
（门开了）
(door opens)
真奇怪.
That's strange.
为什么果酱会让金海豚不受保护？
Why would Marmalade leave the Golden Dolphin unprotected?
-因为这可能是个陷阱-或者也许...
-Because maybe it's a trap. -Or maybe...
-等等，等等，等等-（呻吟）
-Wait, wait, wait! -(groans)
是的，那是个陷阱.
Yeah, it was a trap.
果酱：好吧，好吧，好吧.
MARMALADE: Well, well, well.
如果不是我的宝贝学生.
If it isn't my prized pupil.
你还带来了州长.
And you've brought along the governor.
或者我应该说...
Or should I say...
-深红色的爪子-（喘息、咕哝）
-the Crimson Paw? -(gasps, grunts)
嗯，这是一个多么巧妙的伪装尊邦钻石的方法，
Mm, what an ingenious way to disguise a Zumpango diamond,
把它藏在显眼的地方.
hiding it in plain sight.
你开玩笑吧.
You got to be kidding me.
什么我多愁善感.
What? I'm sentimental.
你总是很有气派.
You always did have panache.
然而，你还是掉进了我的陷阱.
And yet, you still fell right into my trap.
但你怎么知道我们会在这里？
But how did you know we'd even be here?
哦，我从一个朋友那里得到了一点提示.
Oh, I got a little tip from a friend.
-（门开了）-（嘶嘶声）
-(door opens) -(hissing)
嘿，伙计.
Hey, buddy.
挂起来怎么样？
How's it hanging?
-蛇-（蛇笑了）
-Snake. -(Snake chuckles)
我能说什么？我们只是点击了一下.
What can I say? We just clicked.
哦，是吗？为你最喜欢的食物工作感觉如何？
Oh, yeah? How's it feel to be working for your favorite food?
啊，你只是嫉妒
Ah, you're just jealous
错过了本世纪的抢劫案.
to be missing out on the heist of the century.
它拥有一切：
It's got everything:
背叛，流星，精神控制.
betrayal, a meteor, mind control.
我能试穿一下吗？
Can I try it on?
当然，搭档.
Of course, partner.
美好的所有的罪行都没有经过训练.
Nice. All the crime with none of the exercise.
（设备呼呼作响）
(device whirring)
那么那些“善良之花”的说法呢？
What about all that "flower of goodness" talk?
这都是谎言吗？
Was it all just a lie?
差不多，是的.
Uh, pretty much, yeah.
你看，我从来不在乎什么是“好的”
You see, I never cared about what's "good."
只有对我有好处的.
Only what's good for me.
比如说，10亿美元.
Like, say, a billion dollars.
哦，我只是有点刺痛.（笑）
Ooh, I just got a tingle. (laughs)
（蛇笑了）
(Snake laughs)
变坏...
Go bad...
或者回家.
Or go home.
拥抱，完成它们.
Cuddles, finish them.
（两人都在尖叫）
(both screaming)
毒气.
(yelps) Poison gas.
不要吸入.
Don't breathe it in.
（嗅嗅）等一下.
(sniffs) Wait a second.
那不是毒气.
That's not poison gas.
（干呕）
(retches)
-食人鱼：对不起-（喘息）
-PIRANHA: Sorry! -(gasps)
（喘息）
(gasping)
惊喜（笑）
Surprise! (laughs)
什么啊，伙计们.
What? Ah, guys.
我不敢相信是你.
I can't believe it's you.
-你说得对Wolfie-我们感觉到了摇摆，伙计.
-You were right, Wolfie. -We felt the wag, man.
-食人鱼：还有刺痛感-很好，对吧？
-PIRANHA: And the tingle. -It's good, right?
（笑）这太感人了，
(chuckles) This is super moving,
但我们可以晚一点再做吗？
but can we do this later?
感觉我的鳍上有节奏部分.
Feels like I got a rhythm section in my fin.
（拳击）
(beatboxing)
-啊，啊-黛安：啊.来吧
-Ah, ah! -DIANE: Ugh. Come on.
旋转刀片！
Spinning blades!
哦，是的.正当
Oh, yeah. Right.
很抱歉我得到了它.
Sorry. I got it.
-伙计们-（笑声）
-Guys... -(laughter)
很高兴见到你.（叹息）
Am I happy to see you. (sighs)
现在是时候气喘吁吁了
Now it's time to huff and puff
把这只小猪的抢劫案打掉.
and blow this little piggy's heist down.
狼蛛：游戏结束了，豚鼠.
TARANTULA: Game over, guinea pig.
有了这块陨石，我们就能犯罪了
With this meteorite, we will be able to commit crimes
人们只会梦想.
people have only dreamed about.
对一块屁股石头来说还不错.
Not bad for a butt rock.
再一次，这不是...
Once again, it's not a...
-（喘息）-别介意我们.
-(gasps) -Don't mind us.
只是抢劫这个地方.（咯咯笑）
Just robbing this place. (chuckles)
-（轮胎吱吱声）-（呜呜声）
-(tires squealing) -(whooping)
不，不，不！
No, no, no!
（蟋蟀啁啾）
(crickets chirping)
来，凯蒂，凯蒂，凯蒂，凯蒂.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
（猫叫）
(cat meows)
（所有的呼喊声）
(all whooping, hollering)
-好吧-我们做到了！
-All right! -We did it!
现在把这件事告诉局长，澄清你的名字.
Now to get this thing to the chief and clear your names.
奇怪的通常，我们开车远离警察.
Weird. Usually, we drive away from the police.
嘿，奇科，你确定我们阻止了抢劫吗？
Hey, chico, are you sure we stopped the heist?
-对-放松
-Yeah. -Relax.
如果没有陨石，果酱就无法控制它们.
Marmalade can't control them if he doesn't have the meteorite.
那么，谁在开那些卡车？
So, who's driving those trucks?
黛安：陨石.
DIANE: The meteorite.
-它还在传播-哦.
-It's still transmitting. -Uh-oh.
慈善基金.改变计划，伙计们.
The charity money. Change of plan, guys.
Webs，有什么方法可以覆盖吗
Webs, is there some way to override
卡车的导航系统？
the truck's navigation system?
我们需要一些
Uh, we'd need some kind of
磁化交叉电路拦截器.
magnetized cross-circuit interceptor.
你是说这个？
You mean this?
哦！她只是越来越酷！
Ooh! She just keeps getting cooler!
哦，是的！
Oh, yeah!
-（轮胎发出尖叫声）-（喇叭声）
-(tires squeal) -(horn honks)
（鲨鱼的叫声）
(Shark whoops)
-（咕噜声）-哇，哇，哇，哇，哇！
-(grunts) -Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
哦，不.
Oh, no.
我们得分手了.
We got to split up.
韦伯斯，你想去女孩之旅吗？
Webs, you feel like a girls' trip?
嗯，是的.
Um, yes.
狼蛛：稍后，孩子们.（笑）
TARANTULA: Later, boys. (laughs)
（《化学兄弟》中的Go）
("Go" by The Chemical Brothers playing)
*一切都变得越来越难找到*
* Everything gettin' harder to find *
*每个人都疯了*
* Everybody jumpin' out of they mind... *
我想去参加女孩们的旅行.
I want to go on the girls' trip.
*这就是我们开始的地方，你感觉到了吗*
* That's where we begin, you feel it *
*人体模型说，“我们打破了模具”*
* Mannequins say, "We breakin' the mold" *
*破门而入，我们破门而入*
* Breakin' out and we breakin' the codes *
*类似于雅克·库斯托*
* Similar to the Jacques Cousteau *
*到了深处，你全身都湿了，所以你的坦克爆炸了*
* To the depths and you're wet, so your tank explodes *
*所以把它拿出来，让你的身体飞起来*
* So get it out, send your body to flight *
呜呜！
Woo-hoo!
*今晚每个人都有目标*
* Everybody got a target tonight *
*大家都来坐车*
* Everybody come along for the ride *
*所有的鞋钉和哑巴*
* All you studs and you duds... *
-你有保险，对吗-是 啊为什么？
-You're insured, right? -Yeah. Why?
-（咕噜声）-（喇叭声）
-(grunts) -(horn honks)
嘿那是我的车！
Hey! That's my car!
是切维奇，宝贝！（笑）
It's ceviche, baby! (laughs)
（狂吠）
(whooping wildly)
*没时间休息*
* No time to rest *
（嘟嘟声）
(beeping)
*尽力而为*
* Just do your best *
*哦*
* Oh *
-*你听到的不是…*-（音频失真）
-* What you hear is not a... * -(audio distorts)
*我们来这里只是为了让你*
* We're only here to make you *
（笑）
(laughing)
*我们只是来让你*
* We're only here to make you... *
（喘息）
(gasps)
*我们只是来让你走的*
* We're only here to make you go *
*去吧*
* Go *
（笑）
(laughing)
再见，笨蛋.
So long, suckers.
*去吧*
* Go *
-哇，砰！-*去吧*
-Whoop-bam! -* Go *
-*Go*-（对着显示器咯咯笑）
-* Go * -(giggling over monitor)
（轮胎吱吱作响）
(tires squeal)
-*Go*-（猫叫）
-* Go * -(cat yowls)
*去吧*
* Go *
-*去…*-（轮胎吱吱作响）
-* Go... * -(tires squealing)
（欢呼声）
(whooping, cheering)
你从哪里学来的？
Where'd you learn to do that?
我是天生的.
Well, I'm, you know, kind of a natural.
主要是YouTube.
Mostly YouTube.
干得好.
Nice work.
在警察局等我.
Meet me at the police station.
不要迟到.
(singsongy): Don't be late.
我们把这块石头交给局长怎么样？
What do you say we deliver this butt rock to the chief?
-对-（笑）
-Yeah. -(laughing)
*尽力而为*
* Just do your best *
*哦*
* Oh *
*你听到的不是测试*
* What you hear is not a test... *
哦（笑）
Oh. (laughs)
果酱：不，不，不，不！
MARMALADE: No, no, no, no!
那是我偷来的钱.
That's my stolen money.
如果你连这个都做不到，那又有什么用呢
What good are you if you can't even
预测他们的下一步行动？
anticipate their next move?
-哦，那是我的错-对
-Oh, so it's my fault? -Yes.
*我们只是在这里创造你，我们只是在这里创造你*
* We're only here to make you, we're only here to make you *
-*开始.*-（歌曲结尾）
-* Go. * -(song ends)
-头儿-这最好是好的.
-Chief. -This better be good.
相信我，你不会想错过的.
Trust me, you don't want to miss this.
（喘息）看.
(gasps) Look.
（轮胎吱吱作响）
(tires squealing)
给我的小面包涂黄油.
Well, butter my crumpets.
蒂芙尼：会吗？
TIFFANY: Can it be?
坏人要归还陨石？
The Bad Guys are returning the meteorite?
（通过广播）：也许这是我们都需要的感觉良好的故事.
(over radio): Perhaps this is the feel-good story we all need.
-呜呜！是啊-呜呜-好吧
-Woo-hoo! Yeah! -Woo-hoo! -All right!
你们觉得他们会给我们开派对吗？
Do you guys think they'll throw us a party?
是 啊有烟火、馅饼和蛋糕.
Yeah. With fireworks, piñatas and cake.
（轮胎吱吱作响）
(tires squeal)
（叹息）
(sighs)
没有他我们做不到.
We can't do this without him.
他可能是个脾气暴躁的先生...
He might be a Mr. Grumpy Pants...
但他是我们的暴躁先生.
But he's our Mr. Grumpy Pants.
-对-（发动机转速）
-Yeah. -(engine revs)
狼
Wolf!
我开始明白为什么你的朋友甩了你.
I'm starting to see why your friends dumped you.
-我没有朋友-（喇叭声）
-I don't have any friends! -(horn honking)
狼：蛇！蛇
WOLF: Snake! Snake!
狼
Wolf?
蛇，回来！
Snake, come back!
我们需要你，宝贝！
We need you, baby!
你需要我们！
And you need us!
哦，你又来了，把它变成私人的.
Oh, there you go again, making it personal.
我给你最后一次机会把陨石给我.
I'll give you one last chance to give me the meteorite.
哦，是吗？你要怎么做，胡子？
Oh, yeah? What you gonna do, Whiskers?
-这个-（设备呼呼作响）
-This. -(device whirring)
-（隆隆声）-（喘息声）
-(rumbling) -(gasping)
什么...？
What the...?
-（叽叽喳喳）-（鲨鱼喘息）
-(chittering) -(Shark gasps)
我们有可爱的同伴.
We've got adorable company.
趴下！
Floor it!
哇！
Whoa!
也许我不该叫他胡子.
Maybe I shouldn't have called him Whiskers.
（都在尖叫）
(all screaming)
今天早上我醒来的时候，
When I woke up this morning,
这不是我今天看到的.
this is not where I saw the day going.
（都在大喊大叫）
(all yelling, grunting)
狼：来吧.
WOLF: Come on.
（尖叫）
(screaming)
哇，哇，哇，哇.
SNAKE: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
嘿，嘿，让我们把这个调低一点，好吗？
Hey, hey, let's dial this down a notch, huh?
再说，你永远也抓不到他.
Besides, you'll never get him.
他是个很好的司机.
He's too good a driver.
嗯，你说得对.
Hmm. You're right.
但现在我想起来了，也许会更好
But now that I think of it, maybe it would be better
利用他最大的弱点.
to exploit his greatest weakness.
确切地
Exactly.
等待（尖叫声）
Wait. (screams)
（喘息）
(gasps)
哇，哇，哇，哇，哇，哇，哇.等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on.
-等等，等等，等等-（笑）
-Hold it, hold it, hold it. -(laughing)
好的，好的.你赢了.
Okay, okay. You win.
你可以拥有太空石.
You can have the space rock.
好孩子，狼.
Good boy, Wolf.
（设备呼呼作响）
(device whirring)
狼：开车.
WOLF: Take the wheel.
没那么快.
Not so fast.
先把他拉上来，不然我就用这个.
Pull him up first, or I'll use this.
哦，来吧.
Oh, come now.
（咯咯笑）
(chuckling)
去做吧，否则你会失去那块石头的.
Do it, or you'll lose the rock.
如果你坚持的话.
If you insist.
拥抱！
Cuddles!
你想要他？他是你的.
You want him? He's yours.
（咕噜声、喊声）
(grunts, yells)
（尖叫）
(screaming)
蛇不，不，不！
Snake! No, no, no!
-蛇-哦，不！
-Snake! -Oh, no!
（发动机转速）
(engine revs)
（尖叫）
(screaming)
伙计们，我知道这很疯狂，但我们要跳下去.
Guys, I know it's crazy, but we're gonna jump it.
疯子你终于能说我的语言了，奇科.
Crazy? You're finally speaking my language, chico.
（发动机转速）
(engine revving)
我们会成功的！
We're gonna make it!
狼蛛：不！
TARANTULA: No!
（都在尖叫）
(all screaming)
（风呼啸）
(wind whistling)
你回来了.
You came back.
（咕哝）
(grunting)
蛇
Snake.
我应该对你说实话.
I should've been honest with you.
我担心如果你知道
I was afraid that if you knew
我想表现得很好，你...
I-I wanted to be good that you'd...
表现得像个混蛋，再也不和你说话了？
Act like a jerk and never talk to you again?
（笑）：是的.
(laughing): Yeah.
重点是我...我，我，你知道...
Point is I... I-I-I, you know...
是 啊我也爱你，伙计.
Yeah. I love you, too, buddy.
这太美了.
This-this is so beautiful.
你们知道这有多美吗？
Do you know how beautiful this is, you guys?
-（鲨鱼哭泣）-现在...
-(Shark sobbing) -Now...
现在你要让我哭了.
Now you're gonna make me cry.
我知道！
(sobbing): I know!
真可怜，对吧？
So pathetic, right?
来吧，伙计们.
Come on, guys.
谁说结束了？
Who said it was the end?
-（喘息）-（鲨鱼咯咯笑）
-(all gasp) -(Shark chuckles)
（所有的叫声、笑声）
(all whooping, laughing)
（闲聊）
(chittering)
果酱：不，不，不，不要...不，不，拥抱！
MARMALADE: No, no, no, don't... No, no. Cuddles!
我们正在失去高度！
We're losing altitude!
我们正在失去高度！我们要下去了！
We're losing altitude! We're going down!
（呻吟、咳嗽）
(groans, coughs)
怎么搞的？我们爆炸了吗？
What happened? Did we blow up?
这是天堂吗？
Is this heaven?
（咕哝）
(grunting)
警长（笑）：就是这样.
CHIEF (chuckles): That is it.
食人鱼：嘿！
PIRANHA: Hey!
这次你绝对逃不掉.
There is absolutely no way you're getting away this time.
-等等，警长-福辛顿州长？
-Wait, Chief. -Governor Foxington?
-不要这样做-狼：噢！
-Don't do this. -WOLF: Ow!
他们没有偷陨石.
They didn't steal the meteorite.
他们要把它带回来.
They were bringing it back.
哈你怎么知道的？
Ha! How could you know that?
除非除非你在密谋
Unless... unless you were conspiring
和一群已知的罪犯在一起.
with a bunch of known criminals.
好（清嗓子）
Well... (clears throat)
事实上，事实上，
as a matter of fact,
该是我坦白的时候了.
it's time I came clean about something.
事实是我真的...（清嗓子）真的...
The truth is I'm really... (clears throat) r-really...
真的很喜欢救赎弧.
Really a big fan of redemption arcs.
是的，我们知道.
Yeah, we know.
（喵喵）
(mews)
我们跑完了.
We're done running away.
-对-嗯.
-Yeah. -Mm-hmm.
-对-是的.
-Yeah. -Yep.
警长，做你该做的.
Chief, do what you need to do.
什么
What?
你要自首吗？
Y-You're turning yourself in?
我们可能没偷陨石，
We might not have stolen the meteorite,
但我们确实偷了很多其他东西.
but we did steal a lot of other things.
该是我们承担责任的时候了.
It's time we took some responsibility.
开始一个干净的状态.
Start a clean state.
带我们进去，头儿.
Take us in, Chief.
哇，真的吗？
Wow, really?
你终于做到了.
You finally did it.
这是你的时刻，警长.
This is your moment, Chief.
喝进去.
Drink it in.
（喘息）哇.
(gasps) Wow.
你知道，我应该...我应该发表演讲.
You know, I should... I should give a speech.
我我应该，不是吗？
I... Well, I-I should, shouldn't I?
-呃...（咕哝）-（局长清嗓子）
-Uh... (mutters) -(chief clears throat)
我六岁的时候，
When I was six years old,
我决定玩短笛，
I decided that I wanted to play the piccolo,
却发现我的手指
only to find that my fingers were just
对那个脆弱的小仪器来说太强大了.
too powerful for that fragile little instrument.
就在那时我发现了执法.
And that's when I discovered law enforcement.
-（咯咯笑）-（酋长含糊不清地继续说）
-(chuckles) -(chief continues indistinctly)
我为你感到骄傲，沃尔夫.
I'm proud of you, Wolf.
你知道，狐狸和狼没什么不同.
You know, a fox and a wolf are not that different.
州长，你有一件好事要做.
You got a good thing going here, Governor.
所以，原来是坏人的传奇故事
So, it turns out the saga of the Bad Guys
得出了一个简单且完全令人满意的结论.
has come to a simple and totally satisfying conclusion.
虽然我想知道，陨石怎么了？
Though I wonder, what happened to the meteorite?
果酱：拥抱！快点，快点！
MARMALADE: Cuddles! Faster, faster!
蒂芙尼：是果酱教授！
TIFFANY: It's Professor Marmalade!
他要把陨石带回来.
He's bringing the meteorite back.
-嗯？嗯，是的，是的-（人群喧嚣）
-Huh? Uh, yes, yes. -(crowd clamoring)
带来...把它带回来.
Bringing... bringing it back.
这正是我正在做的.
That's precisely what I am doing.
别再看了.
Look no further.
你的英雄来了.
Your hero has arrived.
教授，有什么评论吗？
Professor, care to comment?
我试着帮他们Tiffany，
I tried to help them, Tiffany,
但最后，还是老故事.
but in the end, it's the same old story.
坏人坏人坏人好人好人.
Bad guys bad, good guys good.
真的.太聪明了.
So true. So wise.
此外，为了城市的利益，
Furthermore, for the good of the city,
我已经慷慨地决定接受这块陨石
I have generously decided to take the meteorite
回到我的院子里保管.
back to my compound for safekeeping.
（欢呼声）
(cheering)
他真的要逍遥法外吗？
Is he seriously gonna get away with this?
非常感谢.天哪，你真好.
Thank you. Gosh, you're kind.
为我放弃吧！
Give it up for me!
主任：等一下.
CHIEF: Wait a second.
这不是陨石.
This isn't the meteorite.
-这是一盏灯-（橘子酱喘息）
-It's a lamp. -(Marmalade gasps)
大家：嗯？
ALL: Huh?
-其他人：什么？
-(Snake chuckling) -OTHERS: What?
狼蛛：蛇，你刚才做了什么？
TARANTULA: Snake, what did you just do?
什么？我朋友很伤心，
SNAKE: What? My friend was sad,
我只是在鼓励他.
and I was just cheering him up.
狼蛛：我认为狼是对的.
TARANTULA: I think Wolf was right.
也许我们不只是可怕的恶棍.
Maybe we could be more than just scary villains.
我很坏.你很坏.
I'm bad. You're bad.
让我们一起变坏吧.
Let's be bad together.
你已经达成协议了.
You've got yourself a deal.
-我能试穿一下吗-当然，搭档.
-Can I try it on? -Of course, partner.
-（橘子酱喘息）-别介意我们.
-(Marmalade gasps) -Don't mind us.
只是抢劫这个地方.
Just robbing this place.
（发动机转速、轮胎吱吱声）
(engine revs, tires squeal)
不，不，不！
No, no, no!
但如果那是一盏灯，那么...
But if that's a lamp, where is the...
（蛇咯咯地笑）
(Snake chuckling)
那个老开关.
The old switcheroo.
（呼呼、隆隆）
(whirring, rumbling)
-（爆炸性的嗖嗖声）-（警官们喘着粗气）
-(explosive whooshing) -(officers gasp)
（风声）
(wind whistles)
-（汽车发动机启动）-（呼噜声）
-(car engine starts) -(purring)
（警报声）
(siren wailing)
是屁股.
It's a butt.
（物体在空中呼啸）
(object whistling through air)
（呜咽）
(whimpers)
警长：等等.
CHIEF: Hold on.
这是尊邦戈钻石.
This is the Zumpango diamond.
但这是被...
But this was stolen by the...
（喘息）
(gasps)
用深红色的爪子.
By the Crimson Paw.
我哦，哦，不，不，不.
Me? Oh, oh, no, no, no.
-天哪-果酱：不，不，不.不，你弄错了.
-OMG. -MARMALADE: No, no, no. No, you've got it wrong.
-一个令人震惊的转折-你犯了个大错！
-And a shocking twist. -You're making a huge mistake!
臭名昭著的土匪被称为深红色爪子
The notorious bandit known as the Crimson Paw
-据透露是-不不
-has been revealed to be... -No! No!
...不是别人，正是Marmalade教授.
...none other than Professor Marmalade.
果酱：我不是深红色的爪子.
MARMALADE: I'm not the Crimson Paw.
-她是深红色的爪子-（警报声哀鸣）
-Sh-She's the Crimson Paw. -(sirens wailing)
嘘，她是爪子！
Sh-She's the Paw!
我是善良之花.不
I'm a flower of goodness. No!
哦！那是我的爬行动物.
Ooh! That's my reptile right there.
-这就是我说的！好吧-是 啊
-That's what I'm talking about! All right! -Yeah!
拜托，总得有人摧毁那颗陨石.
Come on, somebody had to destroy that meteorite.
那东西很危险.
That thing was dangerous.
很好，斯纳基.
That was pretty good there, Snakey.
好的这是天才.
Good? It was genius.
我不仅挫败了猪，
Not only did I foil the pig,
我让你承认你有多在乎我.
I got you to admit how much you care about me.
当然可以.
Sure, yeah.
我只是想知道一件小事.
I just wonder about one little thing.
哦，是吗？那是什么，狼？
Oh, yeah? What's that, Wolf?
你觉得是谁把那瓶汽水放进冰箱的？
Who do you think put that one Push Pop in the fridge?
等待
Wait.
你不
You... No.
我就知道你很好.
I knew you were good.
-（笑声）-不.
-(laughter) -No.
-我们很好，宝贝.我们很好-是 啊
-We good, baby. We good. -Yeah!
*你感觉还好吗*
* You feelin' all right? *
*嗯哼*
* Uh-huh *
*我自己感觉不太好*
* I'm not feelin' too good myself *
*嗯哼*
* Uh-huh *
*是的，你感觉还好吗*
* Yeah, you feelin' all right? *
*嗯哼*
* Uh-huh *
*我感觉不太好，小女孩*
* I'm not feelin' too good, little girl *
*嗯哼*
* Uh-huh *
*看来我必须*
* Seems I've got to have *
*场景的改变*
* A change of scene *
*每天晚上，我都有*
* Every night, I have *
*最奇怪的梦*
* The strangest dreams *
*顺便说一句*
* Imprisoned by the way *
*可能是*
* It could have been *
*我一个人留在这里*
* Left here on my own *
*或者看起来*
* Or so it seems... *
沃尔夫：好吧，想象今天是你的生日.
WOLF: Okay, so imagine it's your birthday.
今天是我的生日.
SNAKE: It is my birthday.
狼：是的，我知道.所以，但我们要继续走下去
WOLF: Yeah, I know. So, but we're walking along
你遇到了一个精灵.
and you meet a genie.
好的.他叫什么名字？
SNAKE: Okay. What's his name?
精灵叫什么名字？
What's the genie's name?
是的，我想知道我在跟谁说话.
Yeah, I want to know who I'm talking to.
我不知道，简而言之是精灵还是吉恩.
I don't know, Genie or Gene for short.
所以他给了你三个愿望.
So he offers you three wishes.
为什么是三个？
Why three?
你知道，行业标准.
You know, industry standard.
现在，你想要什么？
Now, what do you wish for?
-呃-祝你们好运，伙计们.
-Uh... -Good luck out there, guys.
我什么都不想去.
I'm gonna go with nothing.
（笑）：什么都没有？
(laughing): Nothing?
来吧，今天是你的生日.
Come on, it's your birthday.
好吧，但我需要什么愿望呢？
All right, but what do I need wishes for?
我得到了自由.
I got my freedom.
-嘿-伙计们！
-Hey. -Guys!
看起来不错，赫尔曼诺斯.
Looking good, hermanos.
-我有我的朋友-狼蛛：哦.
-I got my friends. -TARANTULA: Aw.
我长了一张只有我一半大的爬行动物皮.
I got the skin of a reptile half my age.
我不知道你的年龄有一半，但你看起来不错.
I don't know about half your age, but you do look good.
那是因为你刚刚蜕皮.
Well, that's because you just molted.
-是的-鲨鱼：你闻起来也很香.
-Yes, I did. -SHARK: You smell good, too.
-我很闪亮.我很漂亮-（笑声）
-I'm shiny. I'm gorgeous. -(laughter)
那我们现在该怎么办？
Uh, so what do we do now?
-偷车-食人鱼！
-Steal a car? -Piranha!
我在开玩笑.
I was joking.
这是个玩笑.
It was a joke.
你知道，仔细想想，沃尔夫，
You know, on second thought, Wolf,
也许我想搭个便车.
maybe I'd, uh, wish for a ride.
-哦，是吗？阿拉卡萨姆-（啪的一声）
-Oh, yeah? Alakazam. -(snaps fingers)
（发动机转速、轮胎吱吱声）
(engine revs, tires squeal)
-很好-（笑声）
-Nice. -(laughter)
-嘿，伙计们.准备好开始工作了吗-（喵喵）
-Hey, guys. Ready to get to work? -(mews)
（笑）：嘿.哇.
(chuckling): Hey. Whoa.
狼蛛：哦.
TARANTULA: Aw.
（发动机转速）
(engine revs)
嘿，你.
Hey, you.
这是正确的.过来.
That's right. Come here.
再近一点.
Little closer.
我说靠近点.
I said closer.
现在我们有时间认识了，
Now that we've had some time to get acquainted, uh,
现在没那么可怕了吧？
not so scary now, are we?
韦伯斯，点击.
Webs, hit it.
（“全新的一天”由繁重的演奏）
("Brand New Day" by The Heavy playing)
（发动机转速）
(engine revs)
（笑声，呼喊声）
(laughter, whooping)
*我太激动了*
* Well, I'm so excited *
*没有伪装*
* There's no disguising *
*我在路上*
* I'm on the road *
*进入一个崭新的视野*
* To a brand-new horizon *
*时间是对的*
* Time is right *
*改变这一生*
* To change this life *
*给我阳光*
* Give me the sunshine *
*把灯给我好让我看到*
* Bring me the light so I can see it *
*相信我*
* Believe it *
*我要抓住它*
* I'm gonna seize it *
*这是崭新的一天*
* It's a brand-new day *
*我看得出来*
* I can see it *
*相信我*
* Believe it *
*我要抓住它*
* I'm gonna seize it *
*这是全新的*
* It's a brand-new *
*崭新的一天*
* Brand-new day *
* A brand-new day *
*崭新的一天*
*为了我全新的方式*
* For my brand-new ways *
*谁来告诉我*
* Somebody tell me *
*你准备好改变了吗*
* Are you ready for change? *
-*哦，是的，嗯！-*我知道，我知道*
-* Oh, yeah, huh! * -* I know, I know *
*不同的道路似乎很奇怪*
* Different paths seem strange *
-*哦，是的，嗯！-*当未来的召唤*
-* Oh, yeah, huh! * -* When the future's calling *
*不要浪费时间*
* Don't waste your time *
-*哦，是的，嗯！-*即日*
-* Oh, yeah, huh! * -* Carpe diem *
*去吹你的脑袋*
* And go blow your mind *
-*哦，是的，嗯！-*我看到了光明*
-* Oh, yeah, huh! * -* I've seen the light *
*我来接你*
* And I'm coming to get ya *
-*哦，是的，嗯！-*你得走运*
-* Oh, yeah, huh! * -* You gotta make your luck *
*我得画一幅画*
* Gotta paint the picture *
-*哦，是的，嗯！-*我也是*
-* Oh, yeah, huh! * -* I'm the same same *
-*有不同的想法*-*哦，是的，哈*
-* With a different mind * -* Oh, yeah, huh! *
*新生活让我感觉很好*
* This new life got me feeling right *
*因为我能看到*
* 'Cause I can see it *
*相信我*
* Believe it *
*我要抓住它*
* I'm gonna seize it *
*这是崭新的一天*
* It's a brand-new day *
*我看得出来*
* I can see it *
*相信我*
* Believe it *
*我要抓住它*
* I'm gonna seize it *
*这是全新的*
* It's a brand-new *
*崭新的一天*
* Brand-new day *
* A brand-new day. *